<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="marc" scriptencoding="iso8601"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NN" url="http://archives.nypl.org/scm/20859.xml">scm20859.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the A. Lincoln Harris scrapbook, <date>1920-1930</date></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>The New York Public Library. Schomburg Center for Research in Black Culture, Manuscripts, Archives and Rare Books Division.</publisher><address><addressline>Schomburg Center for Research in Black Culture</addressline><addressline>515 Malcolm X Boulevard, New York, NY 10037-1801</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>EAD generated by archives.nypl.org on <date normal="2014-12-09">December  9, 2014</date></creation><langusage><language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage></profiledesc></eadheader>
  
  <archdesc level="collection"><did><unittitle>A. Lincoln Harris scrapbook</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1920-1930</unitdate><unitid type="local_mss">20859</unitid><unitid type="local_call">MssCol 20859</unitid><origination><persname source="naf">Harris, A. Lincoln</persname></origination><repository><corpname>The New York Public Library. Schomburg Center for Research in Black Culture, Manuscripts, Archives and Rare Books Division.</corpname><address><addressline>Schomburg Center for Research in Black Culture</addressline><addressline>515 Malcolm X Boulevard, New York, NY 10037-1801</addressline></address></repository><physdesc><extent>1 vol</extent></physdesc><abstract>An actor and producer, A. Lincoln Harris reportedly was the first black playwright to feature black people in dramatic works. He produced several plays among them "The Advanced Negro," " Waena," "High Life in Haiti" and "A Trusted Friend" that featured the Lincoln Harris Players founded by Harris. Advertisements and reviews of plays comprise the contents in the scrapbook. The majority of articles, however, deal with the accomplishments of black people especially in sports.</abstract><langmaterial>Materials in English</langmaterial></did><bioghist><p>A. Lincoln Harris was a playwright, producer, actor, and founder of the Lincoln Harris Players. On Broadway Harris was known as the understudy for the leading role in Marc Connelly's, "Green Pastures". He was also reportedly the first black playwright to feature black people in dramatic works. Among the one and two act plays Harris either wrote, appeared in, or produced are: <em render="italic">The Advanced Negro, The Tenth Calvary in Mexico, For Her Father's Sake, Tallaboo, The New Negro, The Colored Gents From the USA, The Government Spy, Richard III, Waena</em> (an all race drama), <em render="italic">What Jealousy Will Do, A Trusted Friend, High Life in Haiti, The Out-Law</em> (two act comedy), <em render="italic">Prince of Hayti</em> and <em render="italic">Dessalines</em>.</p></bioghist><custodhist><p>The collection was donated to Helen Armstead-Johnson, and subsequently donated by her, along with other theater related collections, to the Schomburg Center.</p></custodhist><scopecontent><p>The A. Lincoln Harris scrapbook is undated with the exception of a few items that are dated from the 1920s to the 1930s. The volume contains reviews and advertisements for Harris' one and two act plays and for the theatre company. Plays in which the Lincoln Harris Players were featured include: <em render="italic">The Advanced Negro</em>, <em render="italic">Waena</em>, <em render="italic">High Life in Haiti</em>, and <em render="italic">A Trusted Friend</em>.</p> <p>There is very little information on Harris, his plays, or the theatrical company in the reviews and advertisements. Articles on black people's accomplishments in general and in sports specifically, comprise most of the material in the scrapbook. Among the contents are newspaper articles on Dr. Louis T. Wright (surgeon at Harlem Hospital), Marion Anderson, Augusta Savage, Anita Bush, and Uma Marson (secretary to Haile Selassie). The contents of the scrapbook also include a copy of the Official <em render="underline">Souvenir Album of the Celebration of the 71</em>st <em render="underline">Anniversary of the Emancipation Proclamation and Negro Progress</em> (1934) and the Official Souvenir Journal, <em render="underline">The Message Magazine</em> (1939).</p></scopecontent><prefercite><p>A. Lincoln Harris scrapbook, Schomburg Center for Research in Black Culture, The New York Public Library</p></prefercite><acqinfo><p>The collection was donated to Helen Armstead-Johnson, by Frieda Harris. It was subsequently donated by Helen Armstead-Johnson, along with other theater-related collections to the Schomburg Center.</p></acqinfo><processinfo type="processing"><p>Paula Williams, September 2000</p></processinfo><processinfo><p>Processed as part of the <em render="italic">Blacks on Stage: African-American Theater Arts Collections Project</em>. Funding was provided by the National Endowment for the Humanities, and the City and State of New York.</p></processinfo><controlaccess><persname source="naf">Harris, A. Lincoln</persname><persname source="naf">Johnson, Helen A</persname><corpname source="naf">Helen Armstead-Johnson Theater Collection</corpname><corpname source="naf">Lincoln Harris Players</corpname><subject source="lcsh">African American actors</subject><subject source="lcsh">African American entertainers</subject><subject source="lcsh">African Americans in the performing arts</subject><subject source="lcsh">Theater -- Production and direction</subject><subject source="lcsh">Theatrical producers and directors -- United States</subject><title>Schomburg NEH Blacks on Stage: African-American Theater Arts Collections Project</title><genreform source="ftamc">Reviews (Criticism)</genreform><genreform source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform></controlaccess><dsc><c01 level="file"><did><unittitle>Reviews</unittitle><container type="box">1</container><container type="volume">1</container></did><scopecontent><p><em render="italic">All God's Chillun'</em>, <em render="italic">Green Pastures</em>, <em render="italic">The New Negro</em>, <em render="italic">For Her Father's Sake</em>, <em render="italic">Waena</em>, <em render="italic">Tallaboo</em>, <em render="italic">The Tenth Calvary in Mexico</em>, <em render="italic">What Jealousy Will Do</em>; Articles: Marian Anderson, James Weldon Johnson, Augusta Savage, Joe Louis, and Anita Bush; Printed Material: an <em render="underline">Official Souvenir Album of the Celebration of the 71st Anniversary of the Emancipation Proclamation and Negro Progress</em> (1934) and an Official Souvenir Journal, <em render="underline">The Message Magazine</em> (1939).</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc></archdesc>
</ead>
