<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="marc" scriptencoding="iso8601"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NN" url="http://archives.nypl.org/mss/3623.xml">mss3623.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Aaron Diamond Foundation records, <date>1955-2001</date></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>The New York Public Library. Manuscripts and Archives Division.</publisher><address><addressline>Stephen A. Schwarzman Building</addressline><addressline>Fifth Avenue at 42nd Street, New York, NY 10018-2788</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>EAD generated by archives.nypl.org on <date normal="2014-12-09">December  9, 2014</date></creation><langusage><language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage></profiledesc></eadheader>
  
  <archdesc level="collection"><did><unittitle>Aaron Diamond Foundation records</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1955-2001</unitdate><unitid type="local_call">MssCol 3623</unitid><unitid type="local_mss">3623</unitid><origination><corpname source="naf">Aaron Diamond Foundation</corpname></origination><repository><corpname>The New York Public Library. Manuscripts and Archives Division.</corpname><address><addressline>Stephen A. Schwarzman Building</addressline><addressline>Fifth Avenue at 42nd Street, New York, NY 10018-2788</addressline></address></repository><physdesc><extent>217 linear ft. (521 boxes)</extent></physdesc><abstract>The Aaron Diamond Foundation was a philanthropic foundation in New York City established by Mr. and Mrs. Aaron Diamond for the purpose of serving the public interest. From 1986 until its termination in 1996 the Foundation awarded financial grants to a broad range of charitable and non-profit organizations in various fields including education, bio-medical research, public health, social welfare, human rights, and the performing arts. Most of the grantee organizations were located in New York City. The bulk of the collection consists of grant files arranged alphabetically by year which record the awarding and administration of financial grants to charitable and non-profit organizations in the fields of medical research, education and culture mainly in New York City who appealed to the Foundation for funds for general support or for special projects and programs. The files include correspondence of the executive director with grantee organizations; copies of proposals and other documents including annual reports, auditors' reports, newsletters and miscellaneous printed matter submitted by grantees in support of their requests for funds; and documents relating to the administration of the grants including grant agreement letters, interim and final reports, internal memoranda, grant data worksheets, and other records. Included also are minutes of the Foundation's board of directors; and miscellaneous records including a chronological file of grant agreement letters sent; and a file of correspondence of the executive director acknowledging and rejecting requests for financial aid.</abstract></did><bioghist><p>The Aaron Diamond Foundation was a philanthropic foundation in New York City established by Mr. and Mrs. Aaron Diamond for the purpose of serving the public interest. From 1986 until its termination in 1996 the Foundation awarded financial grants to a broad range of charitable and non-profit organizations in various fields including education, bio-medical research, public health, social welfare, human rights, and the performing arts. Most of the grantee organizations were located in New York City.</p></bioghist><scopecontent><p>The bulk of the collection consists of grant files arranged alphabetically by year which record the awarding and administration of financial grants to charitable and non-profit organizations in the fields of medical research, education and culture mainly in New York City who appealed to the Foundation for funds for general support or for special projects and programs. The files include correspondence of the executive director with grantee organizations; copies of proposals and other documents including annual reports, auditors' reports, newsletters and miscellaneous printed matter submitted by grantees in support of their requests for funds; and documents relating to the administration of the grants including grant agreement letters, interim and final reports, internal memoranda, grant data worksheets, and other records. Included also are minutes of the Foundation's board of directors; and miscellaneous records including a chronological file of grant agreement letters sent; and a file of correspondence of the executive director acknowledging and rejecting requests for financial aid.</p></scopecontent><prefercite><p>Aaron Diamond Foundation records, Manuscripts and Archives Division, The New York Public Library</p></prefercite><arrangement><p>In four series: I. Grant Files; II. Minutes of the Board of Directors; III. Miscellaneous Records; and IV. Additional Records</p></arrangement><acqinfo><p>99M26, 2003M11: Gift, Aaron Diamond Foundation and the Irene Diamond Fund, 05/--/1997</p></acqinfo><accessrestrict><p>Advance notice required.</p><p>Requests for employment (containers #516, 517, 518) are closed until the year 2053.</p></accessrestrict><controlaccess><corpname source="naf">Aaron Diamond Foundation</corpname><subject source="lcsh">Charities -- New York (State) -- New York</subject><genreform source="aat">Color slides</genreform><genreform source="aat">Floppy disks</genreform><genreform source="aat">Sound recordings</genreform><occupation source="lcsh">Philanthropists</occupation></controlaccess></archdesc>
</ead>
