<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="marc" scriptencoding="iso8601"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NN" url="http://archives.nypl.org/mss/920.xml">mss920.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Abner Lord Ely papers, <date>1835-1955 [bulk 1848-1871]</date></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>The New York Public Library. Manuscripts and Archives Division.</publisher><address><addressline>Stephen A. Schwarzman Building</addressline><addressline>Fifth Avenue at 42nd Street, New York, NY 10018-2788</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>EAD generated by archives.nypl.org on <date normal="2014-12-09">December  9, 2014</date></creation><langusage><language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage></profiledesc></eadheader>
  
  <archdesc level="collection"><did><unittitle>Abner Lord Ely papers</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1835-1955</unitdate><unitdate type="bulk">1848-1871</unitdate><unitdate type="bulk">1848-1871</unitdate><unitid type="local_mss">920</unitid><unitid type="local_call">MssCol 920</unitid><origination><persname source="naf">Ely, Abner Lord, 1805-1871</persname></origination><repository><corpname>The New York Public Library. Manuscripts and Archives Division.</corpname><address><addressline>Stephen A. Schwarzman Building</addressline><addressline>Fifth Avenue at 42nd Street, New York, NY 10018-2788</addressline></address></repository><physdesc><extent>1 linear foot (2 boxes)</extent></physdesc><abstract>Abner Lord Ely (1805-1871) was a New York City merchant and real estate manager. He founded the real estate management firm Horace S. Ely &amp; Company in New York City. Collection consists of general and family correspondence, legal and financial papers, and other materials relating mainly to Ely's activities as a dry goods merchant, commission agent, and manager of real estate in New York City. Correspondence, 1832-1871, received from John B. Lesieur, a socially prominent American residing in Paris, France, concerns political events in France and Europe and properties in New York which were managed by Ely. Included is correspondence with members of the Mead family and with Ely's brother John, a lawyer, regarding cases involving mercantile law being tried before the United States Supreme Court. Also, miscellaneous legal and financial papers of other members of the Ely family and a history, 1955, of the firm founded by Ely written by his lineal descendant Richard Ely Nevius.</abstract><langmaterial>Materials in English</langmaterial></did><bioghist><p>Abner Lord Ely (1805-71) was born in South Salem, Westchester Co., New York to Mary Lord (1764-1841) and John Ely (1763-1827), and a Protestant clergyman. His great grandfather, Richard Ely (1610-90) of Plymouth, England, emigrated to America in the latter part of the 17th century. Little is known of his early life excepting that he must have been raised in modest circumstances and according to the precepts of Christian piety. By 1833 Ely had become established in New York City as a dry goods merchant at 259 Pearl Street specializing in the silk trade. In 1836 he founded with his brother Horace the firm Abner L. Ely &amp; Co. at 65 Maiden Lane which, two years later, was dissolved probably as a result of the Panic of 1837. Concomitantly with his dry goods business Ely increasingly engaged in the practice of serving as a commission agent and as a manager of real estate investments in the city for numerous private investors among whom John B. Lesieur (died 1876), a wealthy Virginian who lived for most of his life in Paris, France. By 1854 the dry goods business had been discontinued in favor of real estate management. In that year Ely established with his nephew Horace S. Ely (1832-1904), the son of his brother, Seth Ely, the firm of Horace S. Ely &amp; Co. The firm remained prominent in real estate management in New York for over one hundred years. Ely was married in 1829 to Rhoda Mead who died in 1849. In 1851 he married Elida Burns. By his first wife he had a son, Abner who died young and three daughters, Sophia, Harriet and Emily. He had one daughter, Elsie Patrick, by his second wife.</p></bioghist><scopecontent><p>The bulk of the papers consist of Ely's general correspondence (1832-1871) and family correspondence (1838-1850) both of which consist of letters received. The general correspondence reflects Ely's activities as dry goods merchant, commission agent, and real estate agent in New York City. There is some correspondence of a more general nature relative to political and church affairs including letters from a student at Princeton Theological Seminary who solicited a position as interim pastor at Ely's congregation, the Brick Presbyterian church. Ely's principal correspondent, is John B. Lesieur who wrote approximately 125 letters (1832-71) to Ely from Paris which contain interesting comments on political events in France and in Europe, his attendance at the French court, the Revolution of 1848, the Franco-Prussian War, American politics, social and family affairs, as well as his extensive real estate investments in New York which Included is a set (incomplete of typed transcript were managed by Ely. The family correspondence includes copies of this correspondence. letters from Ely's nephews and cousins, his brothers-in- law, Solomon, Richard and Thomas Mead, his sister-in law, Laura Mead, and his brother John. The correspondence from John Ely/a Lawyer who wrote from Washington, D. C. and from Boston concerns cases involving mercantile law being tried (in part) before the U. S. Supreme Court. The correspondence from his cousin, Seth M. Ely who resided at Ripley, New York concerns shipments of butter and cheese for the New York market.</p> <p>Included also is a mortgage, an indenture, and a copy of an obituary of Ely; and a few legal and financial papers of other members of the Ely family including Horace S. Ely, his nephew, and John Ely, his brother. There is also present a printed pamphlet entitled History of Horace S. Ely &amp; Company of New York (privately printed, 1955) by Richard Ely Nevius (1907 -), a lineal descendant of Abner Lord Ely, together with research notes which Nevius made for his history.</p></scopecontent><prefercite><p>Abner Lord Ely papers, Manuscripts and Archives Division, The New York Public Library</p></prefercite><acqinfo><p>May 14, 1986, Received from Mts. Richard E. Nevius.</p></acqinfo><processinfo type="processing"><p>Accessioned by John Stinson, 7/10/1986</p></processinfo><controlaccess><persname source="naf">Ely, Abner Lord, 1805-1871</persname><persname source="naf">Ely, Horace S</persname><persname source="naf">Ely, John</persname><persname source="naf">Ely, Seth M</persname><persname source="naf">Lesieur, John B., d. 1876</persname><persname source="naf">Nevius, Richard Ely, 1907-</persname><famname source="lcsh">Ely family</famname><famname source="lcsh">Mead family</famname><corpname source="naf">Horace S. Ely &amp; Co. (New York, N.Y.)</corpname><corpname source="naf">United States. Supreme Court</corpname><subject source="lcsh">Commercial law -- United States</subject><subject source="lcsh">Dry-goods -- New York (State) -- New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Real estate management -- New York (State) -- New York</subject><subject source="lcsh">Real property -- New York (State) -- New York</subject><geogname source="lcsh">France -- History -- 1789-1900</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">New York (N.Y.) -- Commerce</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Paris (France) -- History -- 1789-1900</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Paris (France) -- Social life and customs -- 19th century</geogname><occupation source="lcsh">Merchants</occupation></controlaccess><dsc><c01 level="file"><did><unittitle>General Correspondence</unittitle><container type="box">1</container></did></c01><c01 level="file"><did><unittitle>Family Correspondence</unittitle><container type="box">1</container></did></c01><c01 level="file"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle><container type="box">2</container></did><scopecontent><p>Mortgage, indenture and obituary of Ely Papers of other members of the Ely Family History of Horace S. Ely &amp; Co. by R. E. Nevius and research notes for the history.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 level="file"><did><unittitle>Additional papers (87 M 40)</unittitle><unitdate>1835-1889</unitdate><physdesc><extent>3 folders (3")</extent></physdesc><container type="box">2</container></did><scopecontent><p>Additional papers consist of bills and receipts, invoices, rent records, and letters (4 items) of Abner LEly and of Abner L. Ely &amp; Co. pertaining to the management of real properties in New York City, some of the papers reflect Ely as agent for Rutsen Suckley. Included is a cash book (1830-34) of George Suckley in account with the Manhattan Company.</p></scopecontent><acqinfo><p>Circa June 15, 1987, Received from Scott Petersen.</p></acqinfo><processinfo type="processing"><p>Accessioned by John stinson, 6/22/1987.</p></processinfo></c01></dsc></archdesc>
</ead>
