<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="marc" scriptencoding="iso8601"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NN" url="http://archives.nypl.org/mss/3405.xml">mss3405.xml</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Abraham Yates, Jr. papers, <date>1604-1825 [bulk 1760-1796]</date></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>The New York Public Library. Manuscripts and Archives Division.</publisher><address><addressline>Stephen A. Schwarzman Building</addressline><addressline>Fifth Avenue at 42nd Street, New York, NY 10018-2788</addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>EAD generated by archives.nypl.org on <date normal="2014-12-09">December  9, 2014</date></creation><langusage><language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage></profiledesc></eadheader>
  
  <archdesc level="collection"><did><unittitle>Abraham Yates, Jr. papers</unittitle><unitdate type="inclusive">1604-1825</unitdate><unitdate type="bulk">1760-1796</unitdate><unitdate type="bulk">1760-1796</unitdate><unitid type="local_mss">3405</unitid><unitid type="local_call">MssCol 3405</unitid><origination><persname source="naf">Yates, Abraham, 1724-1796</persname></origination><repository><corpname>The New York Public Library. Manuscripts and Archives Division.</corpname><address><addressline>Stephen A. Schwarzman Building</addressline><addressline>Fifth Avenue at 42nd Street, New York, NY 10018-2788</addressline></address></repository><physdesc><extent>2.2 linear feet (5 boxes, 1 v.)</extent></physdesc><abstract>Abraham Yates, Jr. (1724-1796) was an American politician and pamphleteer. A radical Whig who was elected to New York provincial congresses and conventions, he was chairman of the convention (1776-1777) which drafted the first state constitution, served as a state senator from 1777 to 1790, and was mayor of Albany from 1790 to 1796. He wrote anti-federalist pamphlets with his relative, jurist Robert Yates (1738-1801), under the pen-name The Rough Hewer. Collection consists of correspondence, writings, speeches, notes, estate papers, photograph, and printed matter. Correspondence, 1754-1825, concerns the activities of Abraham Yates as a political figure in New York State. Writings, notes and speeches include essays he wrote on the U.S. Constitution, notes on proceedings in Congress, speeches to the delegates to Congress in 1786, The Rough Hewer manuscript, and notes for histories of New York and Albany. Also, papers relating to the Manor of Rensselaerwyck and the Albany Committee of Correspondence, land and family records, photograph of painting of Yates, and other items such as broadsides and a legal treatise by Thomas Wentworth printed in London in 1663.</abstract><langmaterial>Materials in English</langmaterial></did><bioghist><p>Abraham Yates, Jr. was born In 1724 at Albany and died there in 1796. He was a radical whig politician who possessed considerable power and influence in northern New York. Related to the jurist Robert Yates he was, like him, an active revolutionary patriot and anti-federalist. As pamphleteers they shared the pen-name, The Rough Hewer. (See Dict. of American Biography, p. 601-602.)</p></bioghist><scopecontent><p>The collection consists of correspondence, 1754-1825, of Abraham Yates, Jr., George Clinton, Robert Livingston, Jr., Christopher Yates, Robert Yates, Abraham Lansing, and others, concerning the activities of Abraham Yates Jr. as surveyor, Lawyer, Land speculator, sheriff of Albany political colleague and adversary, pamphleteer, anti-federalist, chairman of the Albany Committee of Correspondence, provincial congressman from Albany, Chairman of the convention that drafted the first New York State constitution, state senator, and mayor of Albany. There also are a letter-book, 1779-1782, relating to his office as commissioner for congressional loans to New York State, essays of Abraham Yates, Jr. on the constitution, speeches to delegates to congress, notes for his histories of New York and Albany, papers relating to the Manor of Rensselaerwyck, and to the Albany Committee of Correspondence, some indentures, mortgages, accounts, legal papers, official documents, broadsides relating to Philip Schuyler as a candidate for Senate, Federaoso and Aaron Burr, and support for Jay and Van Rensselaer, and a photograph of a painting of Abraham Yates Jr. The bulk of the collection was bequeathed to Victor Hugo Paltsits who donated it to the library.</p></scopecontent><prefercite><p>Abraham Yates, Jr. papers, Manuscripts and Archives Division, The New York Public Library</p></prefercite><acqinfo><p>1917, 1919, Received from Howard Townsend, 1917 Victor Hugo Paltsits, 1919</p></acqinfo><processinfo type="processing"><p>Accessioned by Richard Salvato, 8-26-85</p></processinfo><controlaccess><persname source="naf">Clinton, George, 1739-1812</persname><persname source="naf">Lansing, Abraham</persname><persname source="naf">Livingston, Robert, 1718-1775</persname><persname source="naf">Wentworth, Thomas, 1568?-1628</persname><persname source="naf">Yates, Abraham, 1724-1796</persname><persname source="naf">Yates, Christopher C., 1778?-1848</persname><persname source="naf">Yates, Robert, 1738-1801</persname><corpname source="naf">New York (State). Convention of the Representatives (1776-1777)</corpname><corpname source="naf">United States</corpname><subject source="lcsh">Real property -- New York (State)</subject><genreform source="gmgpc">Photographs</genreform><geogname source="lcsh">Albany (N.Y.) -- History</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">Albany (N.Y.) -- Politics and government</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">New York (State) -- Constitution</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">New York (State) -- History -- Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">New York (State) -- Politics and government -- To 1775</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States -- Politics and government -- 1775-1783</geogname><geogname source="lcsh">United States -- Politics and government -- To 1775</geogname><occupation source="clsh">Pamphleteers</occupation><occupation source="lcsh">Politicians</occupation></controlaccess><dsc><c01 level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle></did><c02 level="file"><did><unitdate>1754-1786</unitdate><container type="folder">1</container></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unitdate>1787-1825</unitdate><container type="folder">2</container></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>letter-book relating to the work of Yates at Commissioner of the Continental Loan Office for the state of New York</unittitle><unitdate>1779 October 31-1782 August 11</unitdate><container type="folder">2</container></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>journal/copybook</unittitle><unitdate>1754-1758</unitdate><container type="folder">2</container></did></c02></c01><c01 level="file"><did><unittitle>Writings, notes, and speeches</unittitle></did><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Essays</unittitle><container type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent><p>Essays on the Constitution; essays on various political subjects; notes on proceedings in Congress, 1774, Oct. 21-1775, Sept. 25; speeches to the delegates to Congress, 1786; The Rough Hewer manuscript.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Notes for a history of New York; notes on early histories or New York and Albany; notes on ancient revolutions of New York; unsorted notes</unittitle><container type="folder">4</container></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Papers</unittitle><container type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent><p>Papers relating to the Manor of Rensselaerwyck; papers relating to the Supreme Court; Charter of Albany, N. Y.; papers of the Albany Committee of Correspondence; legal papers; mortgages; official documents, last wills and testaments; indentures; accounts; broadsides; and a photograph of a painting of Abraham Yates, Jr. ["The Office and duty of executors: or, A treatise of wills and and executors"] 1663, printed in London Wentworth vol. 1.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Slipcase Notes concerning the early history of N. Y</unittitle><unitdate>1601-1761</unitdate></did></c02></c01><c01 level="file"><did><unittitle>CHRONOLOGICAL LIST</unittitle></did><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>1. Schuyler, Pieter (Mayor- of Albany). A reply to Dom. Godevridue van Dell's application In regard to the highway. A. D. S. 2 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>1688 December 4</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>2. Albany. Article from the Albany Argus of Dec, 10. 1899, relative to the population of Albany In 1697</unittitle></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>3. Ten Eyck, John (Recorder). Bill of costs In the suit of Andries Wies against Sybrant G. Van Schaik. D, S. 1 sma11 piece, no date</unittitle><unitdate>1754 (probably)</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>4. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yetta Esq., High Sheriff for the City and County of Albany. Congratulating him on his appointment as Sheriff and requesting that Patrick Magic he retained as "Jailkeeper", A. L, S. 1 p. folio, dated Manne</unittitle><unitdate>1754 October 7</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>5. Livingston. Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., High Sheriff of the City &amp; County of Albany. Regretting the appointment of Thos. Worrel as Jail keeper. "As to Thos. Morrell perhaps you have not heard that I have promised him swiping </unittitle><unitdate>1754 October 21</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>6. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yetts, Esq., High Sheriff of the Comity of Albany. Requesting him to come down to Claverack and bring a "Writt" Kith him. Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio. dated Claverack</unittitle><unitdate>1754 December 12</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>7. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yets Junr. Esqr. att Albany. "I am told that there is again a Committee to come from Boston to view and layout lands, if not in my [doubt-] at least in the neighbourhood. I hope youll bring more friends a</unittitle><unitdate>1755 January 31</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>8. De Lansey, James, addressed to the Corporation of Albany, I have reason to hope that I shall be enabled to put your town In a better posture of defense than It has hitherto been". "You are sensible no great dependence is to be had on what the French In</unittitle><unitdate>1755 February 10</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>9. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., high Sheriff for the City &amp; County of Albany. "On my Coming home I was informed that Some of my manner people took S new England men in my manner In arms A Carryed them to your Goal by Virtue</unittitle><unitdate>1755 March 3</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>10. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yetta Juar. Esqr., High Sheriff for the City &amp; County of Albany, "With much difficulty I have at last catched Josiah Loomis, the ringleader find first beginner of the troubles with the Boston Government.</unittitle><unitdate>1755 April 14</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>11. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., High Sheriff for the City &amp; County of Albany. "Yours of the 25 ultima was delivered me yesterday at Tackanick were I have been to turn out my rebellious Tenants A pulled down their houses, w</unittitle><unitdate>1755 May 2</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>12. Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. "I am just, ready to set out for Boston from whence I have recd 2 letters that my son Phillip is in a declining State. I am much pleased to hear that your Corporation received General Shirly in a Body </unittitle><unitdate>1755 July 16</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>13. Hardy, Sir Charles, to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr, Refers to the Lieut. Governor's Proclamation &amp; orders Yates to apprehend A carry to Goal all persons in his Bailiwick guilty of Desertion. L. S. 1 p. quarto, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>1755 September 11</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>14. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esq., High Sheriff for the City &amp; County of Albany. "I find that you have sent Patrick down to Consult me. I have reason to believe that he does not intend to Execute that precept you mention", Aut</unittitle><unitdate>1756 February 9</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>15. Swart, Dirck, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. at Albany. Referring to 5 Plates sent up to Yates by Esq. Fonda's Sloop, Also Bill for same, oblong strip In Dirck Swart's autograph. Autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated Manner Livingston</unittitle><unitdate>1756 March 18</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>16. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yetts Esqr. at Albany. Relating to some escapee from Goal and the best measures to take for the recapture of one called Shoemaker, Autograph letter signed 1 p folio, dated Manner Livingston</unittitle><unitdate>1756 March 31</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>17. Murray, Joseph, addressed to William Corry Esquire, Attorney at Law In Albany. Relating to various legal cases, L. S. 2 p. folio, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>1756 August 2</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>18. Banyar, George[DOUBT-], addressed to Abraham Yates Jun. Esq., high Sheriff of the City and County of Albany. Mentions Mr. Silvester. "I apprehend your office of Sheriff will be looked on as incompatible with that of an Attorney". Autograph letter sign</unittitle><unitdate>1756 October 4</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>19. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yetts Esqr., High Sheriff of the City &amp; County of Albany. Relating to Judgments against rebellious Tenants. "We have agreed to give the Govr. L 1800 pr. annum but he Refuses to take it &amp; Insists on havin</unittitle><unitdate>1756 October 20</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>20. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yetts Esqr., High Sheriff of the City &amp; County of Albany, "I returned last night; from New York &amp; shall be glad to see you here the beginning of the next week to execute the Judgments", Autograph letter </unittitle><unitdate>1756 November 16</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>21. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yetta Esqr., High Sheriff for tha City &amp; County of Albany. "I wrote you on my arrival from New York &amp; desiring you to come down to Execute the Judgment a of Court for turning my Rebellious Tenants out of</unittitle><unitdate>1756 November 23</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>22. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yetts Esqr., High Sheriff for the City &amp; County of Albany. "I have bean threatened by Van Golden's Sons to be murdered &amp; burnt down, of which I gott an affidavit of a Sheffield man who heard them say it.</unittitle><unitdate>1756 December 15</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>23. Worth, Johann Jacob, addressed to Mats. Abraham Yates, Sheriff lieving in Albany, Reminding him of his promise to send the under-sheriff to Schoharie. A, L. S. In Dutch, 1 p. folio, dated Schocharie</unittitle><unitdate>1757 April [DOUBT-]</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>24. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yetts Esqr., High Sheriff for the City &amp; County of Albany. "Mrs. Livingston told me that She heard the Rebels were again looking out &amp; marking out farms In My manner" A, L. S. 1 p. folio, dated Manor Liv</unittitle><unitdate>1757 April 14</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>25. Wendell, Harmanus. Draft of his will. Signed by Jacop Pruyn. John Ja. Lansingh &amp; Pet. Silvester as witnesses. D. S. 2 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>1757 April 13</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>26. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yetts Esqr., High Sheriff for City &amp; County of Albany. Repeating the request in a former letter and desiring him to come down without any Loss of time. Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manor Liv</unittitle><unitdate>1757 April 27</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>27. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yetts Junr. Esqr., High Sheriff att Albany. "Sir, Charles told me I should apply to you when ever any attempts were made to Settle or take possession of my Lands". Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dat</unittitle><unitdate>1757 May 9</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>28. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yetts Junr. Esqr., High Sheriff for the City, &amp; County of Albany. Relating to the release from Goal of John Van Gelden &amp; his son. "I fear he will come &amp; burn me down or waylay &amp; kill me, at least he will</unittitle><unitdate>1757 May 15</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>29. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yetts Junr, Esqr., High Sheriff for the City A County of Albany. "I am on my Guard &amp; you'll I suppose not be surprised when you hear that I have Shett him, which I am determined to do the first time I se</unittitle><unitdate>1757 May 18</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>30. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yetts Junr, Esqr., Sheriff of the County of Albany. Enclosing a Proclamation received from Mr. Banyard.. Autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated Manor Livingston</unittitle><unitdate>1757 June 23</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>31. Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Refers to Peter Dow's illness &amp; to Coll. Schuyler. "I often long to hear the news of your town &amp; of the army, which I most generally have Imperfect". Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manor Liv</unittitle><unitdate>1757 July 3</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>32. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yetts Junr. Esqr., High Sheriff of the City &amp; County of Albany. Refers to John Van Gelden'e demand for the restitution of hie horse, saddle, bridle. Guns &amp;c. which had been taken from him when he was com</unittitle><unitdate>1757 July 6</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>33. Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Interesting letter referring to the French &amp; Indian War. "Am heartily glad to hear that the Summerset man of war has been. so fortunate as to take two French Ships with 300 men &amp; is 89000 Sterling, but</unittitle><unitdate>1757 July 19</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>34. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yetts Esqr, att Albany. Inquiring whether Mr. Bleeker intended to come down to run a line for him. Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston</unittitle><unitdate>1757 November 5</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>35. Egbertse, Egbert. His complaint against Alexander McLane. D. 2 p. folio, dated Mayor's Court</unittitle><unitdate>1758</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>36. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., High Sheriff for the City &amp; County of Albany, Interesting letter relating to the expedition against Ticonderoga, "I see General Abercromby &amp; Lord How have made application to Coll. Ren</unittitle><unitdate>1758 February 17</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>37. Wendell, Henry I., addressed to Abraham Yates Esq., Sheriff in Albany. "Lord how has Ordered me Immediately to Proceed With my Company and complete It upon the Mohawk River". Autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>1758 April 4</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>38. Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. "I have been at [doubt-] to assist my Couz's Robert &amp; Henry Livingston in their Election". Autograph letter signed, 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston</unittitle><unitdate>1759 January 11</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>39. Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Interesting letter relating to the politics of Albany, "Both parties have acted impolitic &amp; without that honour &amp; generosity with which citizens ought to treat, one the other, at all times &amp; more Espec</unittitle><unitdate>1759 February 10</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>40. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., High Sheriff of City &amp; County of Albany. Refers to the death of "our old friend, Cap. Winne". "Lett me know what news you have &amp; where the greatest Strength of our Army is gone, Northward or</unittitle><unitdate>1759 June 8</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>41. Livingston, Robert, Junr, addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., High Sheriff for the City, &amp; County of Albany. Interesting letter relating to the French &amp; Indian war. "I am in a Continual dread least I should hear of the French Fleets getting to Quebec be</unittitle><unitdate>1759 June 15</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>42. Banyar, [doubt-], addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., High Sheriff of Albany Enclosing a copy of the. Naturalisation Act &amp; mentioning Sir William Johnson' tenants. "If among the others there are any whom you think really unable to pay the Fee on a</unittitle><unitdate>1759 July 16</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>43. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., High Sheriff for City &amp; County of Albany Interesting letter relating to the French &amp; Indian War. "I beg you to write me the particulars of Niagara &amp; How it came about that Sir William had th</unittitle><unitdate>1759 August 6</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>44. Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Interesting letter referring to Gen. Amherst, Sir William Johnson, Gen. Wolfe, Admiral Rodney &amp; others. "In my opinion If we do not take Canada we shall give very little by this war". Autograph letter </unittitle><unitdate>1759 August 9</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>45. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. att Albany. "I have seen the articles of Surrender of Quebec in our papers, which are also Extraordinary and much of a piece with those of Guadeloupe, neither of which please me. I do n</unittitle><unitdate>1759 November 24</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>46. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. att Albany. Refers to his lot in the "Saratoga Patent". "The French officers make a long tarry on our frontiers, provisions are more plenty there then at Canada", Autograph letter signe</unittitle><unitdate>1760 January 3</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>47. Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr, Referring to Yates having been removed from office by his enemies. "They now begin with me, the Great &amp; mighty Coll, has seazed upon my horses and Sleds". A, L. S. 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston</unittitle><unitdate>1760 January 24</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>48. Livingston, Robert, Junr, to Abraham Yates Junr. "God Grant we may Soon take all Canada &amp; keep It while the world Stands, that we may be relieved from Sundry petto Tyrants who rule with a Rod of Iron the best Subjects the King of Great Britain has in </unittitle><unitdate>1760 February 8</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>49. Cobham, William, addressed to Abraham Yates Esq. at Albany. Stating his account against Lewis Deluxe &amp; putting same in Yates' hands for collection. Autograph letter signed 2 p. folio, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>1760 February 11</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>50. Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Refers to the Albany Library. "God Grant us Success that the Enemy may be obliged to Sue for a peace before the End of this year". Autograph letter signed, 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston</unittitle><unitdate>1760 February 29</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>51. Cobham, William, addressed to Abraham Yates Esq. at Albany. "Mr Hugh Gain has sent all his Accent. to Mr. McComb at Albany". Autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>1760 March 11</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>52. Van Eps, John E., addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates, attorney at Law at Albany, to the care of Joseph Yates at Sehonechdadie. Mentions Andries Gardenier &amp; his brother Jacob. Autograph letter signed in Dutch, 1 p. folio, dated Cagenuwago</unittitle><unitdate>1760 May 22</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>53. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. att Albany. Very Interesting letter containing war news. "I have heard that the French have Raised the Siege of Quebec on the appearance of our fleet. I shall order a good fat Oxen to b</unittitle><unitdate>1760 May 30</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>54. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Mr, Abraham Yates Junr., Merchant in Albany. Refers to the Albany election, certain lands in Saratoga Patent, making mention, of Col. Bradstreet, the Bleeckers, Ten Broecks and De Ridders, &amp; closing as follows: </unittitle><unitdate>1760 July 17</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>55. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. att Albany. Refers to the damage to crops caused by heavy rains all the way from Fishkill up to Albany. "I expect our Army is now in motion This is a time we ought above all others to h</unittitle><unitdate>1760 August 11</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>56. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates Junr. att Albany. Refers to the good news that "our Armies are new In possession of all Canada". Also mention Yates desirs to again obtain the office of Sheriff. A, L. S. 1 p. folio, dated Mano</unittitle><unitdate>1760 September 3</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>57. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr. att Albany I have this day wrote to my Brother Philip &amp; William to wait on his Honr. the President and to desire the favour of him in my name to appoint you Sheriff for the Ensuring; year. "A</unittitle><unitdate>1760 September [doubt-]</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>58. Whitney, Thomas, addressed to Abraham Yates Esq, at Alban;. Asking him. to "take Gear" of two "Rites" Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Clouvriack</unittitle><unitdate>1760 October 6</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>59. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates Junr., Merchant In Albany. "I Long to hear what voyages your Albany Gentlemen have made to Canada. I also want to know how the Troops are to be disppsed of now the war is at an End in our Quart</unittitle><unitdate>1760 October 13</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>60. Whitney, Thomas, to Abraham Yates Junr. Telling him he had settled his Action with Robert Noble. Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Clouvarieck</unittitle><unitdate>1760 October 29</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>62. Yates, Abraham, Junr. Draft of letter in his autograph. Relative to the sale of certain lands. Autograph letter signed 2 p. folio, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>1760 October 29</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>63. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Eaqr. att Albany Refers to the sale of lands in the Saratoga Patent by the Bleekers, Mr, Ten Broeck &amp; Shuyler &amp; "your old uncle Killiaen. "I imagine your City must Inlarge that way, while no </unittitle><unitdate>1760 November 7</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>63. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esq. att Albany. "But how your uncle Killiaen will sell any I am at a lose to know, as I heard some time ago that there was some difficulty in his Tittle". Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated</unittitle><unitdate>1760 November 13</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>64. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. att Albany. Refers to Killiaen De Ridder's title to lands in the Saratoga Patent. "I hear it hinted from New York that we are going to have an Expedition, this winter to the Massasappie</unittitle><unitdate>1760 December 10</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>65. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. In Albany Refers to a petition addressed by the Corporation of the City of Albany to "the President &amp; Council". "I Congratulate you on the Victory Lately gained by the King of Prussia, </unittitle><unitdate>1765 January 22</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>66. Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Referring to the election in Albany &amp; mentioning various candidates. "If you are Inclinable to Sett up with Mr. Abraham Ten Broeck, whom I Look upon to be without any flattery the two best Qualified in</unittitle><unitdate>1761 February 4</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>67. Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Referring to the coming Election &amp; the difference of opinion existing between Yates &amp; Tan Broeck. Mentions Sir William Johnson, "who undoubtedly has great Interest". "As for my part while my friends ar</unittitle><unitdate>1761 February 6</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>68. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. att Albany. Refers to Yates standing for the coming election. "The Camps will not move to an Election without being payed for- their time at 4 e/ pr. man. The Gentlemen of the other Sid</unittitle><unitdate>1761 February 8</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>69. Livingston, Robert, Junr. Unsigned draft, copy of a letter sent by Livingston to Messrs. Douw &amp; Ten Eyck. It was enclosed In Livingston's letter to Yates, bearing date Feb. 16, 1761. "As my friend; Mr. Ab, Yates wrote me. the 4 Current that he Intende</unittitle></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>70. Yates G Junr., addressed to [DOUBT-] Junr., Merchant att Albany. Refers to dishonorable methods used at elections. "I see you are like to have new Troubles upon your Corporation for Incroachments by the Township of Schenectady. Autograph letter signed</unittitle><unitdate>1761 February 16</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>71. Yates, Abraham, Junr. Draft of letter to Robert Livingston in his autograph. [DOUBT-], interesting letter relating to the Election In Albany. Mentions Abraham Ten Broeck's dishonorable conduct toward Yates, Sir William Johnson's influence ac. 6 p, fol</unittitle><unitdate>1761 February 16</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>72. Yates, Abraham, Junr. "We are apprehensive that we will be obliged to contend with the Inhabitants of Schonectady about the Bounds and Jurisdiction of our City". Endorsed; "A. Yates Junrs., observation on Limits of the City 1761". D. 4 p. folio, dated</unittitle><unitdate>1761 February 21</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>73. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates Junr., Merchant att Albany. Refers to Yates failure at the recent Election. "You have now experienced what dependence there is on that frail Creature Called man. I hope however you have not pai</unittitle><unitdate>1761 March 26</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>74. Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yats Junr. Refers to Yates desire to be appointed Sheriff-on the death of the person then holding the office. A. L, S. 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston</unittitle><unitdate>1761 May 11</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>75. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Mr. James Stevenson, Merchant In Albany. "I have ordered my young man to go up with the pitts-jagos &amp; to Carry as much bar Iron for you as It will conveniently load". Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Ma</unittitle><unitdate>1761 July 9</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>76. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esq. in Albany, Refers to Mr, Stevenson &amp; some business with the Sheriff. "As head Quarters Is now in your City, doubtless you have all the news Running, as I here am barren must Entreat you to Com</unittitle><unitdate>1761 July 21</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>77. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esq. att Albany. "I was in great hopes that after the Reduction of all Canada arbitrary power and all other Illegal proceedings by the Gentlemen of the army would have been at an End. You tell me a</unittitle><unitdate>1761 July 28</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>71. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esq. att Albany. Refers to the disposition of the troops then stationed on Staten Island; to the War on the Continent; mentions Cell. Grant, Sir William Johnson &amp; Gen, Monckton, "I have not heard t</unittitle><unitdate>1761 August 5</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>79. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, att Albany. Wishes Hendrick Bogart to come down to put a new bottom in his Sloop. "The fleet is Saild I hear for Barbados their to make the randevous for gethering the whole fleet &amp; army toge</unittitle><unitdate>1761 December 2</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>80. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., attorney at Law In Albany. An Interesting letter relating to affairs in Germany, Spain, Denmark, Russia &amp;.; also commenting on domestic news. "By the Speech of his Honr. to the Assembl</unittitle><unitdate>1761 December 8</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>81. Wendell, Harmanus H.; addressed to his father, Harmanus Wendell, Merchant in Albany, "Mr. John Fry tells me he has Been Drunk For Six Weeks upon a Stretch and is So Every Day". Autograph letter signed, 1 p, folio, dated Schenectady</unittitle><unitdate>1762 January 16</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>82. Wendell, Harmanus. Memorial addressed by Harmanus Wendell, Lucas Van Veghten &amp; another to Sir Jeffery Amherst, Commander in Chief of all his Majesties forces In America, requesting a Pass to go from Albany to Montreal. Draft of Document in autograph o</unittitle><unitdate>1762 January 23</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>83. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., Attorney at Law In Albany. Referring to a "white Seader Swamp" &amp; enclosing a letter of Yates, relating to Yan Bergen's land. A, L. S, 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston</unittitle><unitdate>1762 February 8</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>84. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., attorney at Law In Albany. Referring to the unpleasant feeling existing between the late &amp; present Mayors, &amp; mentioning the sale of lots In the Saratoga Patent. Autograph letter signed</unittitle><unitdate>1762 March 4</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>85. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., attorney at Law In Albany. Mentions Killeen De Ridder, Mr Lydius, Mr. Stevenson &amp; Mr. Silvester. "A Spanish War seems to threaten &amp; perhaps we are on the Eve of it. It's true we are at</unittitle><unitdate>1762 March 13</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>86. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Attorney at Law In Albany. Refers to the request of the English "Prisbaterians" for a meeting-house, where the "Grenery" now stands. "I Congratulate you on the Reduction of Martinico, </unittitle><unitdate>1762 April 19</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>87. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Attorney at Law In Albany. "I want to hear how our army at Martinico is to be disposed of for the Summer Season and what other Expeditions we are to undertake". Autograph letter signed</unittitle><unitdate>1762 May 8</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>88. Duncan, John, addressed to Mr. William Corry Esq. in Albany. Refers, to the costs of some suit. Autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated Schenectady</unittitle><unitdate>1762 August 17</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>89. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham, Yates Junr. Esqr. att Albany. Referring to trouble in the church &amp; mentioning the birth of a child in Yates' family. "I am just going to a bon Fire I have Caused to be Erected as a testimony of our Joy </unittitle><unitdate>1762 September 13</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>90. Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter in his autograph to Robert Livingston. Refers to the division of a Patent "that join on the Half Moon". "Antony Van Schayck Brake the chain, after some Discourse about the Consequences of Shopping the Commissione</unittitle><unitdate>1762 September 27</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>91. Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Referring to Coll. Van Rensselaer's meeting with his tenants and the validity of their leases, Also mentions Mr. Jeremiah Van Rensselaer. Autograph letter signed, 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston</unittitle><unitdate>1762 December 2</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>92. Corry, William, addressed to Mr, Joseph Howard, Merct. In Montreal. Enclosing a bond of Hans Legars due to Alexander McKay. "The news., at present is the peace by which Canada is [doubt-] to the; English. Autograph letter signed 1 p, folio, dated Alba</unittitle><unitdate>1763 March 11</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>93. Williston, John, addressed to Mr. Wm. Yates att Albany Atorney att. Law. Asking advice as to how he should proceed in his action with Parsons. Autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated Springfield</unittitle><unitdate>1764 July 18</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>94. Van Rensselaer, Jeremiah, addressed to Robert Yates Esqr., Attorney at Law, Albany. Asking him to arrest immediately one Jacob of Cloverack. "John Mc Combes has Settled with me Autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>1764 September 9</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>95. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Samuel Dunham. Draft of letter in his autograph. Relative to his suit with Thoma Smith Junr. of Charles Town, South Carolina, 1 p. quarto</unittitle><unitdate>1764 September 13</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>96. Van Rensselaer, Stephen. Receipt given by him to Abraham Yates Junr. D. S. 1 p. folio, in autograph of Peter W. Yates and also signed by him</unittitle><unitdate>1764 September 17</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>97. Winne, Jellis. His bill against Abm. Yates Junr., the same being receipted July 10, 1765. A. D. S, in Dutch, 1 p, small quarto</unittitle><unitdate>1765 January</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>98. McKay, Alexander. His bill against Jno. McFall for the amount of which he brings suit. D. S, 1 p, folio, addressed to Mr. Abraham Yatts Esqr. Attorney at Law in Albany</unittitle><unitdate>1765 February 7</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>99. Ten Eyck, Jacob C. (Judge), Affidavit of Christian Ehl In his case against Thomas Winn. D. S. 1 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>1765 May 25</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>100. Yates, Abraham, Junr. His affidavit relative to the head of a wolf brought before him by Michael Lantman. A. D. S. 1 small square</unittitle><unitdate>1766 November 4</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>102. Yates, Robert. Copy of Complaint of Thomas Winn, through Robert Yates his attorney, against Christian Aile, for selling him a bay stallion under false pretences &amp; asking damages to the extent of eighteen pounds. D. 2 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>1767 January</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>103. Silvester, Peter. Bill of costs In suit of Janneke Van Hoosen against Dirck Van Derheyden, receipted by Silvester as Attorney for Defendant. D. S. 1 p. quarto</unittitle><unitdate>1767 May 19</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>103. Wendell, Evert. Draft of Indenture (part of it in the autograph of Abm. Yates Junr.) between Evert Wendell &amp; Hendrick Wendell of Sinckhaick, of the one part, and John Johannis Fonda, son of Susanna, one of the daughters of Abm. Wendell doc'd, of the </unittitle><unitdate>1767 June</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>104. De Lancey, Stephen (Clerk). Order issued to the Sheriff of Albany County to sell the "chattels, lands &amp; Tenements of James Howells" to satisfy his debt to John Magee. Indorsed on the back by Har. Schuyler, sheriff. D. S. oblong strip</unittitle><unitdate>1767 June 5</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>105. Yates, Peter. Indenture &amp; Copy of Mortgage Bond of house and lot in the second ward of the city of Albany. D. S. by Peter Yates, Johannis Saml. Pruyn, Matthew Visscher, Christopher P. Yates &amp; others. 5 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>1767 November 16</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>106. Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter to Alexander McKay. Relative to his various legal suits. 2 p. quarto, dated, Albany</unittitle><unitdate>1768 February 8</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>107. Taylor, William, addressed to Mr. [DOUBT-] La Grange Living at the Hellebargh. Mentioning his father's will &amp; advising him to subject Ary La Grange to a strict cross-questioning regarding the same. Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Hellebargh</unittitle><unitdate>1769 March 23</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>108. Rogers, John, addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates, Attorney at Law in Albany, Asking information regarding some case at law. A, L. S, 1 p, folio, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>1768 September 24</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>109. Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed to Mr, Hyde, some of Capt. Hide at Sarachtoge, Behind Walran Clute. Requesting him to some down, get his Lease &amp; pay the Debt which his father owed, L, S. 1 p. quarto, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>1769 April 11</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>110. Wendell, Harmanus, Draft of his Will, part of it in the writing of Abraham Yates Junr. D, 4 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>1769 May 25</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>111. Winne, Anthony, addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates at Albany. Requesting him to collect from Peter Bronck the money he was owing Winne for a load of hay. Autograph letter signed 1 p. small quarto, dated Cosakkey</unittitle><unitdate>1769 September 5</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>112. Van Schaick, Wessel, Two Bills of Exchange drawn on Mesers, Sargent Chambers &amp; Co., Merchants in London, in favor of Wessel Van Schaick &amp; signed by Reade &amp; Yates, D, 1 p, quarto, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>1770 August 24</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>113. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Saml., Jones Esqr. In behalf of Corporation. Requesting his opinion in a case. Autograph letter draft</unittitle><unitdate>1771 February 3</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>114. Yates, Abraham, Junr., Relating to the first settlement of Albany, "I now propose to add the reasons that induces me to think that the West India Company by Virtue of their Grant from the States of Holland had no right to the Possessions, Commons &amp; o</unittitle><unitdate>1771 March 19</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>115. Ten Eyck, Henry, Junr. His receipt for 42 pounds 6 shillings. D. S. 2 p, quarto</unittitle><unitdate>1771 May 14</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>116. Banyar, George, to the Hon. Robert R. Livingston &amp; George Duncan Ludlow, Esquires. "Some Time after the last River- Circuit I was informed that the Mayor and Magistrates of the City of Albany had, in an Address transmitted to the Lieutenant Governor,</unittitle><unitdate>1771 June 5</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>117. Jones, Samuel, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr Esqr. in Albany. "It seems the first Settlers of Albany either conquered or purchased the Lands of the Indians. I suppose they settled as Subjects and under the Protection of the States General in which </unittitle><unitdate>1771 July 12</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>118. De Lancey, Stephen (Clerk). Order issued to the Sheriff of Albany County to bring one Benjamin Springer before the next Inferior Court of Common Please. A. D. S. oblong strip</unittitle><unitdate>1772 January 24</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>119. Yates, Abraham. Complaint made by John Mahoney, through Abraham Yates, his attorney, against Benjamin Springer for failure pay him various sums of money borrowed from said Mohawney. D. 3 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>1772 June</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>120. De Lancey, Stephen (Clerk). Order Issued to the Sheriff of Albany County to bring John Mohany before the next Inferior Court of Common Pleas. D. S. oblong strip</unittitle><unitdate>1772 June 5</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>121. Douw, Volckert P, (Judge). Referring to Benjamin Springer's delivery to Bail. D. S. 1 p. quarto</unittitle><unitdate>1772 September 22</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>122. Mohawney, John. An order to pay to Cornelius Glen the amount due him. Signed by Matthew Visscher, Abraham Yates Junr. &amp; Cornelius Glen. D. signed by Mohawney's mark, 1 p, folio, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>1772 September 30</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>123. Winn, John, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr, Asking him to call on his as soon as possible to give his advice regarding action toward his creditors. Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Albany City Hall</unittitle><unitdate>1773 May [DOUBT-]</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>124. Schuyler, Philip; Ten Broeck, Abraham; Livingston, Peter R.; addressed to Abraham Yates Esq. Chairman of the Committee of Correspondence, Albany. Interesting letter relative to important decisions of the House of Assembly. "You will at one glance per</unittitle><unitdate>1774 February 25</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>125. Yates, Richard. Order on Messrs Sargent Chambers &amp;Co, of London to pay one hundred pounds to Evert Bancker or. Endorsed by Evert Bancker. A, D. S. oblong strip, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>1774 March 23</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>126. Yates, Abraham, Junr Drafts of a letter A resolutions passed at a meating of the committee of Correspondence of the City &amp; County of Albany. Refers principally to the needs of the inhabitants of Boston. &amp; the determination of the citizens of Albany t</unittitle><unitdate>1774 December 10</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>127. Low, Isaac (Chairman), to Mr, Jacob Lansing, Chairman of the committee of the City and County of Albany. Relating to some goods for warded to Mr, Abraham Schuyler &amp; Mr. Andrew McFarlin. Autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>1774 December 15</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>128. Six Nations. Document, 3 p. quarto, part in autograph of Abn. Yates Junr. Endorsed: - "Answer of the Six Nations to the Speech of the 12 United Colonies 1775"</unittitle></did><scopecontent><p>Also, Document, 1 p. quarto, endorsed "Speech to the Indians when they recd the Presents".</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>129. Bleecker, Henry. to John N. Bleecker &amp; Rutger Bleecker, Committee. Stating two questions on which it is requested "that the Inhabitants of this ward Signify their assent or Dissent", D S. 1 p. folio, dated Albany, Also signed by Jacob Bleecker" Jacob</unittitle><unitdate>1775 March 21</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>130. Yates, Robert, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Chairman of the Committee, Albany. Introducing Col. Flemming, "A gentleman appointed by this Congress adjutant General to the Army under the [doubt-] of General Schuyler". Autograph letter signed</unittitle><unitdate>1775 September 6</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>131. Brewster, Samuel, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esquire, Albany. "As the only members of the Committee of Safety now present we forward this to you &amp; pray you to make the best use of the Intelligence &amp; your Time". L. S. 1 p. folio, dated New Yor A</unittitle><unitdate>1776 January 2</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>132. Gansevoort, Leonard, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr, Chairman of the Committee of the City and County of Albany. Transmitting parcells of pamphlets. "The Congress met yesterday morning and preceeded to business. The Ships of War in this Harbou</unittitle><unitdate>1776 February 13</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>|33. Benson, Robert (Secretary). A copy of Resolves of Congress to give Money on Loan to the Counties mentioned. A. D. S. 2 p. folio, dated In Provincial Congress, New York</unittitle><unitdate>1776 March 13</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>134. McKerlie, John. His affidavit concerning Ensign Howard, "The people seem to be suspicious of General Schuyler and his proceedings and that they were also suspicion that the Provisions going were for the use of the King's Troops". D. S. 1 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>1776 May 18</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>135. Jansen, Dirck, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Chairman off the Committee at Albany. Asking for six Gentlemen to come down to assist the Militis of Dutchese County of their movement against the disaffected people in his District D. S, 1 pf fo</unittitle><unitdate>1776 May 19</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>136. Yates, Christopher P., addressed to Abraham Yates Esq, and in. his absence to Matthew Visscher Esq, in Albany. Interesting letter asking assistance from the Albany Committee. "We have just reed. Intelligence by Express from Oneida that a large Body o</unittitle><unitdate>1776 June 8</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>137. Yates, Abraham, Junr, Draft of letter in hia autograph, endorsed- "to Rt. Yates". Concerning the sale of some wine, Small square piece, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>1776 June 10</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>138. Gansevoort, Leonard. Interesting Document also signed by Philip Livingston (the Signer), Thos. Randall, Gouv. Morris, Thomas Fred- well &amp; Lewis Graham Summon to Wb. Backers of Westchester Co., Issued by a Committee of the Congress of the Colony of Ne</unittitle><unitdate>1776 June 27</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>139. Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed to the Committee of Albany, Also signed by Mat. Adgate A Jno. J. Bleeckar. "Yesterday a Committee was appointed to draw up &amp; Resolve to Put you under a Peremptory Rule to furnish the Congress with your Proceedings aga</unittitle><unitdate>1776 July 26</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>140. Visscher, Matthew, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr. An intersting letter, narrating the experiences of Maj. Bigelow, who was sent with a flag from our Array to the Commander of the British Troops. A, L. S. 3 p. folio, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>1776 August 19</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>141. Yates, Robert. Interesting document giving extracts from the Resolves of the Committee of Safety for the State of New York, In reference to the purchase of wheat for the use of the Continental Army and the execution of certain coopers from militia du</unittitle><unitdate>1776 October 29</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>142. Wisscher, Matthew, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Kingston. Interesting letter referring to the condition of Schoharie, mentioning Gen. Arnold as "gone to the westward", &amp; repeating Col. Willett's interesting description of affaire at Fort S</unittitle><unitdate>1777 August 15</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>143. Congress, Committee of. Copies of letters sent to His Excellency George Clinton, Govr, of the State of New York. Also several copies of letters of Gen. Washington. "We again entreat you in the most earnest, in the most urgent Manner, to use every Exe</unittitle><unitdate>1780 May 25-June 23</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>144. Clinton, George (Gov.), copy of his letter to Congress. Explaining the inability of New York State to comply with the requisitions of Congress. 16 p. folio., dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>1781 February 5</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>145. Yates, Christopher P., addressed to Henry Glen Esq., A. D, Q. M. Genl. Schenectady, Declining to accept a sent in either House of the Legislature, for family reasons. "As to major Frey I know his Sentiments on the Subject so well that I am well convi</unittitle><unitdate>1781 April 7</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>146. Morris, Robert, to his Excellency, The Governor &amp; Commander in Chief of the State of New York. Concerning the account of the United States against the State of New York. "Your Excellency must be sensible of the Impracticability of carrying on the War</unittitle><unitdate>1781 July 16</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>147. Morris, Robert. to Governor Clinton. Concerning, the account against the State of New York for specific supplies &amp; asking information of Gov. Clinton on various points. A, L. S. 5 p. folio, dated Philadelphia</unittitle><unitdate>1781 July 25</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>148. Morris, Robert, probably addressed to Gov. Clinton. Pointing out the erroneous ideas held by Americans as to the financial aid given by France, Spain &amp; Holland to the United States. "Not a single State has acknowledged our Independence except France"</unittitle><unitdate>1781 October 19</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>149. Clinton, George (Governor), copy of his letter to His Excellency, John Hanson Esq., President of Congress. Also Copy of Resolutions of the Senate &amp; Assembly of the State of New York of the 21st November 1731. "They entertain very slender Hopes of the</unittitle><unitdate>1781 November 24</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>150. Morris, Robert (probably). Part of a letter, presumably sent by Morris either to the President of Congress or to the Governor of the State of New York, explaining at length his scheme for funding the national debt D. 24 p. quarto, dated Office of Fin</unittitle><unitdate>1782 July 29</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>151. L'Hommedieu, [DOUBT-], addressed to the Honble Abraham Yates Junr. Esquire, Albany. Refers to Yates' desire to obtain the position of Receiver of Taxes; mentions the acknowledgment of American Independence by Holland; the death of Col. Lawrence near </unittitle><unitdate>1782 August 2</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>152. Morris, Robert, to the commissioners for Settling Accounts of the States. Copy of Document made by William Barber &amp; signed by Morris. The whole Is endorsed: - "Queres proposed by the Auditors appointed to settle the Acts. of the States of Maryland &amp; </unittitle><unitdate>1782 September 7</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>153. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to James Duane Esq. Refers to his disappointment In not being appointed Receiver of Taxes. "I have had the Loan Office over three years without a Copper In pay". Draft of letter in Yates' autograph, 2 p. folio, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>1782 September 7</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>154. Morris, Robert, to Abraham Yates Esq., Loan Officer for New York. "You will be pleased to transmit me all the Bills of Exchange now In your Office". L. S. 1 p. quarto, dated Office of Finance</unittitle><unitdate>1782 September [DOUBT-]</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>155. Duane, James, to Abraham Yates Junr. An Interesting, letter stating the Financier's (Morris') reasons for keeping the offices of Receiver and Loan Officer separate. Autograph letter signed 4 p. quarto, dated Philadelphia</unittitle><unitdate>1782 September 15</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>156. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to The Honble Robert Morris Esq., Superintendent of Finance. Refers to a Bill of Exchange which he will transmit with the Returns for the present month, Draft of letter. 1 p. quarto, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>1782 September 21</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>157. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to the Honble Robert Morris Esq., superintendent of Finance. Transmitting a Return for the Month of September and also a Bill of Exchange. Draft of letter. 1 p. small quarto</unittitle><unitdate>1782 October 4</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>158. Yates, Abraham, Junr.. draft of letter to the Hon'ble James Duane &amp; Ezra L'Hommedieu. An interesting letter giving the substance of a conversation with Coll. Hamilton. "I told him I thought the Financier had too much Power already and that Congress h</unittitle><unitdate>1782 October 19</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>159. Morris, Robert, to Abraham Yates Junr. esquire, Contl, Loan Officer for the State of New York. "You will receive from the Treasurer of the United States a Discharge for the Bill of Exchange therein mentioned". L. S. 1 p. quarto, dated Office of Finan</unittitle><unitdate>1782 October 23</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>160. McCall, J. (Secretary), to Abraham Yates Esqr., Commissioner of the C. L. 0. for the State of New York. Concerning a Bill of Exchange, L. S. 1 p. quarto, dated Office of Finance</unittitle><unitdate>1782 October 23</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>161. L'Hommedieu, Ezra, addressed to The Honorable Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Albany, favoured by Colo. Gonsavolt (Gonsevoort), Referring to his demands for compensation for his services as Loan Officer. "The Prospects of Peace are not so favourable as th</unittitle><unitdate>1782 October 28</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>162. Loan Office. Endorsed: - "Return for October 1782 Copy", D. 2 p. quarto</unittitle></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>163. Appleton, Nathaniel, addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates Junr., Commisr. of Loans N. York, Albany. "My case is not in all respects similar to yours, but I am equally excluded from receiving the Continental Taxes, Mr. Morris apologized for this". A, L. S. </unittitle><unitdate>1782 November 1</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>164. Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter to the Honbl. Robert Morris Esq., Superintendent of Finance, Philadelphia. "I am exposed to Inconveniences by having devoted three whole Years to Service of the public for which I have not hitherto with repeated</unittitle><unitdate>1782 November 4</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>165. Morris, Robert, to Abraham Yates Esqr., Loan Officer of the State of New York at Albany. "As to the request you make of Money I am very sorry to say that it is not in my Power to comply with it". L. S. 2 p. quarto, dated Office of Finance</unittitle><unitdate>1782 November 29</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>166. Petry, William; Frank, John; Fox. Friedenrich, Their appraisal of certain lands forfeited by John Tompson. Endorsed: - "The within, supposed to have been sold by Gen. Gansevoort &amp; Jeremiah Van Rensselaer". D. S., 1 p. quarto, dated Johnstown</unittitle><unitdate>1785 February 10</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>167. Howell, David (Judge), addressed to Honorable Abraham Yates Junr. Esquire, Albany, "The period will doubtless arrive when the Liberties of this country will fall a sacrifice, but I hope in God that It Is not nigh. I hope the Rough Hewer will continue</unittitle><unitdate>1785 July 12</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>168. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Judge David Howell. Refers to the pamphlets of Dr. Price &amp; the Abbe De Mably &amp; the five points discussed in them, relative to the dangers threatening the Government. draft of letter in Yates' autograph, 2 p. quarto, dated Al</unittitle><unitdate>1785 August 28</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>169. Gensevoort, Leonard. Addressed to the newspaper, relative to the superior claims of Abraham Ten Broeck to receive the suffrages of his countrymen rather than Abraham Yates. D. 7 p. folio, signed "A Freeholder"</unittitle><unitdate>1786</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>130. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., New York. Referring to Bills of the New Emission, Loan Office accounts recently examined by Col. Barber and "Certificates and vouchers to the amount of about 50,000 dollars. now in his hand</unittitle><unitdate>1786 January 25</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>171. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Abraham G. Lansing (probably), "I am making ready to Dine at the Gover's where I expect to see Coll. Moron and some others that probably will give me information of the Loan office". Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated</unittitle><unitdate>1786 February 1</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>172. Bancker, Gerard (Treasurer). Receipt given Abraham Yates Junr. for "Interest facility Certificates" amounting to $72. 405. A. D. S. 1 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>1786 February 20</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>173. Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed te Abm. G. Lansing, Post Master, Albany. Mentions Duer, Bancker, Osgood &amp; refers to the Oath of Office which he was required to take. A, L. S. 2 p. folio, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>1786 March 1</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>174. Osgood, Samuel; Livingston, Walter; Lee, Arthur, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., New York. "It is our Duty to remind you. that until you have taken the Usual Oath of Office we cannot Consider you as a Commissioner of the Loan Office under the</unittitle><unitdate>1786 March 1</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>175. Visscher, Matthew, to Abraham Yates Esq. Refers to a Petition of George G. Klock's &amp; touches upon many political points. "Does not the Confederation expressly declare that Delegatee shall be annually appointed and take their Seats In Congress on the </unittitle><unitdate>1786 March 6</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>176. Osgood, Samuel; Livingston, Walter; Lee, Arthur, to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. Transmitting a Resolve of Congress In reference to the Oath of Office &amp; returning the Oath left by Yates at the office of the Board of Treasury. L. S. 2 p. quarto. dated Bo</unittitle><unitdate>1786 March 28</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>177. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Mr, Hendrick Gardineer, near Upper Ferry. Referring to the approaching election and the "Great Exertions made by the Manor and Schuyler Interest to prevent the Election of our Old Friend Abraham Yates Junr". "They ar</unittitle><unitdate>1786 April 19</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>178. Smith, William, addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr, in Albany. Refers to him serious illness &amp; sending remembrances to his friends in Albany, A, L. S. 1 p. folio, dated Manr. St, George</unittitle><unitdate>1786 July 18</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>179. Yates, Abraham, Junr. draft of his letter to William Smith, Long Island. Expressing sympathy on account of his illness &amp; extending an invitation to himself &amp; wife to make a visit in. Albany. 2 p. Quarto, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>1786 July 27</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>180. Lansing, Abraham G. to Abraham Yates Junr, Referring to a Report of the Loan Office &amp; mentioning Col. Barber, Mr. Livingston, Mr. Osgood &amp; others. Also mentions Mr. Bancker's serious injury by a fall from a horse. "The Business of the State will in c</unittitle><unitdate>1785 December 3</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>181. Milligan, James (Comp, of the Treasury), to "The Honorable The Board of Treasury". Refers to the settlement of Abraham Yates Junr's accounts as Loan Officer. Copy of document, 4 p. large folio, dated Comptroller's Office</unittitle><unitdate>1786 December 9</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>182. Barber, William, to Abraham Yates Esquire, Bespeaking his assistance in procuring an appointment as a member of the Board of Commissioners. A. L, S. 2 p. quarto, Bated Poughkeepsie</unittitle><unitdate>1787 February 1</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>183. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. to the cars of Wm. Bedlow Esqr., New York. Relating to Loan Office matters, an altercation; with the Treasury Board &amp;c "Barber's situation is perhaps delicate from the prospect be has of con</unittitle><unitdate>1787 April 8</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>184. Yates, Robert, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Member of Congress at New York. Refers to the Philadelphia Convention. "Additional Rules have since been entered Into, one of which strictly prohibits the communication of its business until the </unittitle><unitdate>1787 June 1</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>185. Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter in his autograph. Refers to canvassing the votes for Senator. 1 p. folio, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>1787 June 2</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>186. Lansing, Abraham G., to Abraham Yates Junr, "The Election for representatives in Assembly has gone against us Gansevoort, Ten Eyck, Gordon, Van Ingen, Van Orden, Younglove &amp; Sickles Mrs. Robert Livingston of the Manor Is also Dead". Autograph letter </unittitle><unitdate>1787 June 4</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>187. Silvester, Peter, addressed to The Honble Abraham Yates Esqr., New York. Concerning the overpayment of a certain Mr, Beache, Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Kinderhook</unittitle><unitdate>1787 June 19</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>188. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junior Esquire, New York. Refers to his brother John Lansing Jr. and Mr. Hamilton. "We have reports hers that Mr, Paine is employed to write in favor of the British form of Government - and that the sys</unittitle><unitdate>1787 August 26</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>189. Yates, Peter W., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr., Leonard Gensevoort &amp; John D. P. Ten Eyck, Esquires, Pokespsy. Refers to a petition presented to the Legislature by Mary Elmendorph. Autograph letter signed 2 p. folio, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>1988 January 21</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>190. Lott, Abraham, to The Honorable Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. of the Senate at Poughkeepsie. Refers to hie confinement in Goal &amp; a Memorial which he wished to have laid before the Legislature. Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>1788 January 22</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>191. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Poughkeepsie. "I am of Opinion that the Measures adopted by Massachusetts Bay will give a tone to the determination of this Important Matter in our Legislature. It is roundly asserted here </unittitle><unitdate>1788 January 23</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>192. Smith, Melancton, addressed to The Honl. Abraham Yates Junr. Esq., Poughkeepsie, "Report here said that you was defenct and that your funeral had been solemnised with great pomp, We have nothing authentic from, the Convention of Massachusetts. The de</unittitle><unitdate>1788 January 23</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>193. Smith. Melancton, addressed to The Honl. Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Poughkeepsie Refers to the adoption of the Constitution. "He advises that the Sum granted as a donation should be acknowledged as a debt, and Included In the Obligations given to the</unittitle><unitdate>1788 January 28</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>194. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., to the care of the postmaster, Poughkeepsie. "Politics are still at a stand. A report has been circulated here for some days informing that the Convention of Massachusetts had rejected the </unittitle><unitdate>1788 January 31</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>195. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Abraham G. Lansing. "Antifederal Business is Carried on in this County with spirit. New York they are all in a panic with the adopt ion. of Massaahusetts", A. L, S. 1 p. folio, Dated Poughkeepsie</unittitle><unitdate>1788 February 28</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>196. Lansing, Abraham G. a copy of Document addressed to Melancton Smith Esq., signed by Abra G. Lansing, John Lansing Junr., Jeremiah Van Renseelaer &amp; others. Requesting that a printer be sent up from New fork with his press to look after the publication</unittitle><unitdate>1788 March 1</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>197. Lansing, Abraham G., to Abraham Yates Junr. The body of the letter refers to the desire of Lansing &amp; his friends to have an unprejudiced printer in Albany. A postscript in handwriting of &amp; signed by Henry Oothoudt, A. L, S. 2 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>1788 March 2</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>198. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., to the house of Mr. Powers, Poughkeepsie. "Our Measures have hitherto a most favourable aspect and if we Continue our Exertions we have the greatest prospect of success". Autograph letter s</unittitle><unitdate>1788 March 12</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>199. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Abraham G, Lansing, Relating to politics. "They Honour me with being at the head of that party and to that end have bean all the scurrilous publications". Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Senate Room, Poughkeepsie</unittitle><unitdate>1788 March 14</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>200. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Abraham G, Lansing. "Wether We will breake up this week and when is made uncertain by Mr. Duane, Lawrence and Vanderbilt arrived here (It is said) for the express purpose of Carrying the Legislature to New York", Autograph l</unittitle><unitdate>1788 March 18</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>201. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr, in Congress, New York. "The Majority of the Assembly is much greater than we had reason to expect. Communicate the agreeable information to his Excellency and all our Friends". Autograph let</unittitle><unitdate>1788 May 27</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>202. Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed to Abm. G. Lansing Esq., Albany. Reports a conversation held with Col. Hamilton. "I told him rather than to adopt the Constitution I would risk a government of Jew. Turk or Infidel. I told him the government that were</unittitle><unitdate>1788 May 28</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>203. Visscher, Matthew, addressed to Ab. Yates Junr., John McKesson and Melancton Smith Eaqr., New York. "The Antifederalists had a Majority in every District except the City of Albany". Autograph letter signed 2 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>1788 May 30</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>204. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. in Congress, New York Refers to the returns of the recent election &amp; the probability of a Majority In the State. "Should any System be proposed with you it will be well to forward a Sketch o</unittitle><unitdate>1788 June 1</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>205. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Abraham G. Lansing. Refers to the Assembly Election &amp; the hopes of the Federalists for the adoption of the Constitution. A. L S. 1 p. folio, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>1788 June 1</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>206. Smith, William, to Abraham Yates Esqr. Refers to the New Constitution. "It Strikes me with Amasement that Good Whigs who Suffered and underwent what they Did Should turn tail too". Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manr. St. George</unittitle><unitdate>1788 June 12</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>207. Van Rensselaer, Jeremiah, to Abraham Yates Junr. "The Montgomery Delegates are Expected in torn this Evening. Judge Oothoudt, the Mayor and such others as May be Ready Embark this Evening With Capt. Van Woert for Poughkeepsie". Autograph letter signe</unittitle><unitdate>1788 June 13</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>208. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., New York. "It appears to be the opinion of all those whom I have conversed with that the Constitution will be effectually emended previous to its adoption - or that it will be Totally rejec</unittitle><unitdate>1788 June 15</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>209. Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed to Abraham G. Lansing Esq., Post Officer, Albany. Refers to the adoption of the Constitution. "The members from this place seem determined not to adopt (without previous amendments) the all the others should. What ste</unittitle><unitdate>1788 June 15</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>210. Oothoudt, Henry, addressed to Honorable Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. In Congress, New York. "On the 17th the Convention met - 53 Members present, The Chancellor opened with along Oration - Moved a Resolution that the Proposed plan of Government be Discu</unittitle><unitdate>1788 June 21</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>211. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. to the care of Willm, Bedlow Esqr., New York. Refers to the Constitutional. Convention. "This Circumstance the Federal gentleman will no doubt avail themselves of and procrastinate the Busin</unittitle><unitdate>1788 June 22</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>212. Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed to Abm. G. Lansing Esq., Post Master, Albany. Refers to his suit against Claxton, the printer, &amp; gives some of his Ideas in regard to the education of children, Autograph letter signed 2 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>1788 June 23</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>213. Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed to Abraham G. Lansing Esqr., Albany. "Whilst I am writing advise is brought that New Hampshire had adopted the New Constitution which bread such an inattention to the Business the Southern Members to write letters to </unittitle><unitdate>1788 June 25</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>214. Yates, Abraham, Junr., 2 drafts of letter in his autograph to the Governor, Refers to the news from New Hampshire &amp; the Loan from Holland. "L'Hommedieu last Monday mentioned that he had from a strong Federal (Dr. Tillotson) that the Anties went upon </unittitle><unitdate>1788 June 27</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>215. Yates, Christopher P., addressed to the Hon, Abraham Yates Esq., In Congress, New York, Interesting letter In relation to the adoption of the Constitution. "The Federalists appear much elated by the adoption of the Constitution in N. Hampshire. ' We </unittitle><unitdate>1788 June 27</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>216. Oothoudt, Henry, addressed to Honorable Abraham Yates Junr. in Congress, New York, "Yesterday we Proceeded to the Consideration of the first Clause of the 8th Section of the first Article". A, L. S. 1 p. folio, dated Poughkeepsie</unittitle><unitdate>1788 June 27</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>217. Clinton, George (Gov.), to the Honble Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. "The Convection are assembling and In a few minutes I must take the Chair. The Antis are firm &amp; I hope and believe will remain so to the End". Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated P</unittitle><unitdate>1788 June 28</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>218. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr. to the care of William Bedlow Esqr., New York. An interesting letter referring to the Convention. "The Federalists here plume themselves much on the accession of New Hampshire, They can now </unittitle><unitdate>1788 June 29</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>219. Yates, Abraham, Junr. addressed to Abraham G. Lansing, Post Master. Albany. It appears that the Anties are neither to be frowned or flattered out of their opinion". Also refers to the lean made in Holland &amp; the proposal to make a new loan. Autograph </unittitle><unitdate>1788 June 29</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>220. Yates, Christopher P., addressed to Hon. Abraham Yates Esquire, New York. Interesting letter referring to a heated argument between Mr. Lansing and Mr. Hamilton in the Constitutional Convention, on the necessity of the existence of the State governme</unittitle><unitdate>1788 June 30</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>221. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr., New York. Referring to a quarrel In the city of Albany between the Federalists and the Antis, caused by "our Friends and their Antagonists being heated with Liquor". "I hope If the Constitu</unittitle><unitdate>1788 July 9</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>222. Lansing, Abraham G. addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esq., New York- Referring to the Constitutional Convention. "Mr. Jones it is said is so much Intimidated by the Threats of the Federalists that he does not any more take as active part. M. Smith is</unittitle><unitdate>1788 July 20</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>223. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esquire, New York. Referring to the plans of the Federalists in Albany for a celebration in honor of the adoption of the Constitution. "The Bill of Rights which is interwoven with the adoption is </unittitle><unitdate>1783 August 3</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>224. Yates, Abraham, Junr., part of the Document in his autograph. Endorsed: - "Minutes of the Convention which formed the Constitution of the State of New York". Refers to the manner of carrying on elections for Senators &amp; the duties of the Governor &amp; ot</unittitle><unitdate>[1777]</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>225. Yates, Abraham, Junr. A statement of his reasons for voting for the new Constitution, tho he was opposed to it in principle. Also an acknowledgment of the receipt of the above declaration, signed by Ezra L'Hommedieu, Egbert Benson &amp; Alexander Hamilto</unittitle><unitdate>1788 August 8</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>226. Lansing, Abraham G., to William Barber. Original draft of letter. Referring to the Commissioners of Forfeitures and also to Mr. Robert Barber, "a young gentleman who served some part of his time with Webster and in the Course of a Month I hope he wil</unittitle><unitdate>1788 August 31</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>227. Metcalfe, George. Acknowledgment of himself an author of an article in the Federal Herald Feb. 18 1788 derogatory to Abraham Yates Junr. &amp; admitting the falseness of the same. Also signed by Thos. Q. Witbeck &amp; Abrm, Reynolds. A. D. S. 1 p. folio, dat</unittitle><unitdate>1789 April 25</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>228. Burr, Aaron, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Albany. Refers to his illness for several weeks, "I shall consider myself engaged as your Counsel". Autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>1790 June 13</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>229. Yates, Robert. Ordering the Sheriff to discharge from custody Thomas as Lewis Spotten &amp; James Spotten of the town of Lansingburg. P. S. 3 p. large folio</unittitle><unitdate>1790 November 5</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>230. Yates, Abraham, Junr. Also signed by John H. Cook &amp; John De Wandelaer as witnesses. William Angell's warrant of Attorney to Abraham G. Lansing. In autograph of Abm. G. Lansing. D. S. 2 p. folio. AlsoYates, Abraham, Junr., in handwriting of Abm. G. La</unittitle><unitdate>1791 February 25</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>231. Yates, Robert. discharge of Joseph Tobias, who had been confined in the Albany jail. D. S. 2 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>1791 March 3</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>232. Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter- to Aaron Burr. This draft was apparently sent to Robert Yates Esq, for his approval before sending the letter to Burr. Refers to the case against Mr. Ten Broeck, for which Burr was Yates' attorney. 2 p. quarto</unittitle><unitdate>1791 April 24</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>233. Ten Broeck, Dirck, addressed to the Honbl Abrahan Yates Junr. Esquire, Albany, Referring to some document which he enclosed in the letter, Autograph letter S, 1 p. folio, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>1791 June 16</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>234. Ten Broeck, Dirck, to the Honbl, Atom. Yates Junr. Esqr. An acknowledgment of his error in Judgment as an Inspector of Election in not allowing Abraham Yates' suffrage. A. D. S. 2 p. folio, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>1791 June 16</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>235. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Dirck Ten Broeck Esq. Relative to the withdrawal of Yates' suit against Ten Broeck. "As the Injury is of a public as well as private nature it is my intention Directly to publish the Certificate", Draft of letter, 1 p. quart</unittitle><unitdate>1791 June 18</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>236. Ten Broeck. Dirck. An acknowledgment of his error in refusing Yates' vote &amp; agreeing to pay all the costs of the suit brought against him by Yates. A. D. S. 1 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>1791 July 25</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>237. Leonard, Enoch An acknowledgment of his error as Inspector of Election in refusing Abm. Yates' vote, &amp; agreeing to pay all the costs of the suit brought against him by Yates. A. D. S. 1 p. folio</unittitle></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>238. Yates, Christopher P., addressed to Mr. John Pourteous, Referring to three Judgments against some small estates. Autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto</unittitle><unitdate>1791 August 14</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>239. Jay, John (Chief Justice), addressed to The Hon'ble Ab. Yates Esq., Mayor of the City of Albany, Written in the third person, declining Mr. Yates' invitation to take breakfast with him. A. D. 1 p. quarto</unittitle><unitdate>1792</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>240. Ten Broeck, Abraham (Chairman), Abraham Yates Junr's license for six years to use the books of the Albany Library. Also signed by James Van Ingen, Treasurer. D. S. 1 small square, printed form</unittitle><unitdate>1793 April 10</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>241. Yates, Abraham, Junr. (Mayor). An Act of the Corporation of the City of Albany "allowing, &amp; permitting a Ferry Stairs to be erected the Wharf opposite to Mark Lane". D. S. 1 p. folio, dated in Common Council</unittitle><unitdate>1793 June 21</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>242. Political Broadside. Announcement "To the Electors of the State of New York". Requesting the electors to support Jay and Van Rensselaer and containing the names of over 80 prominent citizens of New York. Double-page printed folio</unittitle><unitdate>1795 February 10</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>243. Ten Broeck, Abraham. Printed Broadside, recommending Gen, Philip Schuyler as a Candidate for the vacant seat of a Member of Senate, Signed by Abm. Ten Broeck as Chairman. 1 p. folio, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>1795 April 2</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>244. Federalism. Printed Broadside, signed "A Republican Elector, Herkimer, April 27, 1807"</unittitle></did><scopecontent><p>Vigorous attack upon the Federalists and Burr. 1 p. folio.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>245. Yates, Joseph C. (Governor), addressed to Christopher Y Lansing. Esquire, Albany. Subscribing for 500 shares of stock of the Commercial Bank. L. S. 1 p. quarto, dated Schenectady</unittitle><unitdate>1825 May 29</unitdate></did></c02></c01><c01 level="file"><did><unittitle>ALPHABETICAL LIST</unittitle></did><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Albany Article from the Albany Argus of Dec. 10, 1899 relative to the pop ulation of Albany in 1697</unittitle></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Appleton, Nathaniel, addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates Junr., Commisr. of Loans N. York, Albany. "My case is not in all respects similar to yours, but I am equally excluded from receiving the Continental Taxes. Mr. Morris apologized for this"</unittitle></did><scopecontent><p>Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Boston Nov 1, 1782.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Bancker, Gerard (Treasurer). Receipt given Abraham Yates Junr. for "Interest Facility Certificates" amounting to $72,405. A. D. P. 1 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>dated February 20, 1786</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Banyar, [DOUBT-], addressed to Abrahan Yates Jun. Esq., high Sheriff of the City and County of Albany. Mentions Mr. Silvester. "I apprehend your office of Sheriff will be looked on as incompatible with that of an Attorney"</unittitle></did><scopecontent><p>Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated New York Oct. 4, 1756.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Banyar, [DOUBT-], addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., High sheriff of Albany</unittitle></did><scopecontent><p>Enclosing a copy of the Naturalization Act &amp; mentioning Sir William Johnson' tenants. "If among the others there are any whom you think really unable to pay the Fee on account of their Poverty, I shall leave it with you to forgive the whole or a part as you think proper". A, L. S. 1 p. folio, dated New York, July 16, 1759.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Banyar, [DOUBT-], to the Hon. Robert R. Livingston &amp; George Duncan Ludlow, Esquires</unittitle></did><scopecontent><p>"Some Time after the last River Circuit I was Informed that the Mayor and Magistrates of the City of Albany had, in an Address transmitted to the Lieutenant Governor, asserted in Virtue of the Charter a Right of being appointed Justices of Oyer &amp; Terminer", D. 1 p. folio. copy of original, signed by Richard Morris, dated New York, June 5, 1771.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Barber, William, to Abraham Yates Esquire, Bespeaking his assistance in procuring an appointment as a member of the Board of Commissioner</unittitle></did><scopecontent><p>Autograph letter signed 2 p. quarto, dated Poughkeepsie, Feb. 1, 1787.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Benson, Robert (Secretary). Resolves of Congress, signed by him, to give Money on Loan to the Counties mentioned</unittitle></did><scopecontent><p>Autograph document signed, 2 p. folio, dated In Provincial Congress, New York, March 13, 1776.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Bleecker Henry, to John N. Bleecker &amp; Rutger Bleecker, Committee. Also signed by Jacob Bleecker, Jacob Cuyler, Barent Roseboom &amp; others. Stating two questions on which it is requested "that the Inhabitants of this ward Signify their assent or Dissent"</unittitle></did><scopecontent><p>Document signed, 1 p, folio, dated Albany, March 21, 1775.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Brewster, Samuel, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esquire, Albany. Also signed by Jno, Morin Scott, Pierre Van Cortlandt, Paul Spooner &amp; others. "As the only members of the Committee of Safety now present we forward this to you &amp; pray you to make the bes</unittitle></did><scopecontent><p>Letter signed, 1 p. folio, dated New York, Jan. 2, 1776.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Burr, Aaron, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Albany. Refers to his illness for several weeks. "I shall consider myself engaged as your Counsel"</unittitle></did><scopecontent><p>Autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated New York, June 13, 1790.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Clinton, George (Gov.), copy of his letter to Congress. Long letter explaining the inability of New York State to comply with the requisitions of Congress</unittitle></did><scopecontent><p>16 p. folio, dated Albany, Feb. 5. 1781.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Clinton, George (Gov.), copy of its letter to his Excellency, John Hanson Esq., President of Congress</unittitle></did><scopecontent><p>Also, Copy of Resolutions of the Senate &amp; Assembly of the State of New York of the 21st November 1781. "They entertain very slender Hopes of their Ability in the present exhausted Condition of the State to comply with any of the Requisitions of Congress". In all 7 p. folio, dated Poughkeepsie, Nov, 24. 1781.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Clinton, George (Gov.), to the Honble Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. "The Convention are assembling and in a few Minutes I must take the Chair. The Antis are firm &amp; I hope and believe will remain so to the End"</unittitle></did><scopecontent><p>Autograph letter, L. 1 p. folio, dated Poughkeepsie, June 28, 1788.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Cobhar, William, addressed to Abram. Yates Esq. at Albany, Stating his account against Lewis Deluxe &amp; putting same in Yates hands for collection. autograph letter signed 2 p. folio, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>February 11, 1760</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Cobham, William, addressed to Abraham Yates Esq. at Albany. "Mr. Hugh Gain has sent all his Accts. to Mr. McComb at Albany", autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>March 11, 1760</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Congress, Committee of. Copies of letters sent to His Excellency George Clinton, Gov, of the State of New York. Also several copies of letters of Gen. Washington, "We again entreat you in the most earnest, in the most urgent Manner, to use every Exertion </unittitle><unitdate>May 25, 1780-June 23, 1780</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, Committee of. Drafts of a letter. part of it in the autograph of Abraham Yates Junr., and also resolution passed at a meeting of the Committee of Correspondence of the City &amp; County of Albany, Refers principally to the needs of the Inhabit</unittitle><unitdate>December 10, 1774</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Corry, William, addressed to Mr. Joseph Howard, Merct, In Montreal. Enclosing a bond of Hans Legars due to Alexander McKay. "The news at present is the peace by which Canada is seded to the English". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>March 11, 1763</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>De Lancey, James, addressed to the Corporation of Albany. "I have reason to hope that I shall be enabled to put your town in a batter-posture of defence than it has hitherto been. You are sensible no great dependence is to be had on what the French Indian</unittitle><unitdate>February 10, 1755</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>De Lancey, Stephen (Clerk). Order issued to the Sheriff of Albany County to sell the "chattels, lands &amp; Tenements of James Howells" to satisfy his debt to John Magee. Indorsed on the back by Har. Schuyler, Sheriff. D. S. oblong strip</unittitle><unitdate>dated June 5, 1767</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>De Lancey, Stephen (Clerk). Order Issued to the Sheriff of Albany County to bring one Banjamin Springer before the next Inferior Court of Common Pleas. A. D. S. oblong strip</unittitle><unitdate>dated January 24, 1772</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>De Lancey, Stephen (Clerk). Order Issued to the Sheriff of Albany County to bring John Mohany before the next Inferior Court of Common Pleas. D. S. oblong strip</unittitle><unitdate>dated June 5, 1772</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Douw, Volckert P (judge). Referring to Banjamin Springer's delivery to Bail. D. S. 1 p. quarto</unittitle><unitdate>dated September 22, 1772</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Duane, James. to Abraham Yates Junr. An interesting letter stating the Financier's (Morris') reasons for keeping the offices of Receiver and Loan Officer separate. autograph letter signed 4 p. quarto, dated Philadelphia</unittitle><unitdate>September 15, 1782</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Duncan, John, addressed to Mr. William Corry Esq. In Albany, Refers to the costs of some suit. autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated Schenectady</unittitle><unitdate>August 17, 1762</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Egbertso, Egbert. Complaint against Alexander McLane. D. 2 p. folio. dated Mayor's Court</unittitle><unitdate>1758</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Federalism. Printed folio Broadside, signed "A Republican Elector, Herkimer, April 27, 1807"</unittitle></did><scopecontent><p>Vigorous attack upon the Federalists and Burr.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Gansevoort, Leonard, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Chairman of the Committee of the City and County of Albany. Transmitting parcells of pamphlets. "The Congress met yesterday morning and proceeded to business. The Ships of War in this Harbour se</unittitle><unitdate>February 13, 1776</unitdate></did><scopecontent><p>Also signed by Henry Oothoudt &amp;. Robert Van Rensselaer.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Gansevoort, Leonard. Interesting document, also signed by Philip Livingston (the Signer), Thos. Randall, Gouv. Morris, Thomas Tredwell &amp; Lewis Graham. Summons to Wm. Badkers of Westchester Co., issued by a Committee of the Congress of the Colony of New Yo</unittitle><unitdate>June 27, 1776</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Gansevoort, Leonard. addressed to the newspaper, relative to the superior claims of Abraham Ten Broeck to receive the suffrage of his countrymen rather than Abraham Yates. D 7 p. folio, signed "A Freeholder", in autograph of Leonard Gansevoort</unittitle><unitdate>1786</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Hardy, Sir Charles, to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. Refers to the Lieut. Governor's Proclamation &amp; orders Yates to apprehend &amp; carry to Goal all persons in his Bailiwick guilty of Desertion. L. S. 1 p. quarto, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>September 11, 1755</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Howell, David (Judge), addressed to Honorable Abraham Yates Junr. Esquire, Albany. ''The period will doubtless arrive when the Liberties of this country will fall a sacrifice, but I hope In God that it is not nigh. I hope the Rough Hewer will continue to </unittitle><unitdate>July 12, 1785</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Jansen, Dirck, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Chairman of the Committee at Albany. Asking for six Gentlemen to come down to assist the Militia of Dutchess County in their movement against the disaffected people In his District. D. S. 1 p. folio, </unittitle><unitdate>May 19, 1776</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Jay, John (Chief Justice), addressed to The Hon'ble Ab. Yates Esq., Mayor of the City of Albany. Written in the third person and declining Mr. Yates invitation to take breakfast with him. A. D. 1 p. quarto</unittitle><unitdate>1792</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Jones, Samuel, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr., In Albany. "It seems the first Settlers of Albany either conquered or purchased the Lands of the Indians. I suppose they settled as Subjects and under the Protection of the States General in which Cas</unittitle><unitdate>July 12, 1771</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., New York, Refers to Bills of the New Emission, Loan Office accounts recently examined by Col. Barber and "Certificates and vouchers to the amount of about 50. 000 dollars now In his hands for ap</unittitle><unitdate>dated January 25, 1786</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Mr. Hendrick Gardineer, near Upper Ferry. Refers to the approaching election and the "Great Exertions made by the Manor and Schuyler Interest to prevent the Election of our Old Friend Abraham Yates Jun". "They are only ca</unittitle><unitdate>April 19, 1786</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Lansing, Abraham G., to Abraham Yates Junr, Refers to a Report of the loan Office &amp; mentioning Col. Barber, Mr. Livingston, Mr. Osgood &amp; others. Also mentions Mr. Bancker's serious injury by a fall from a horse. autograph letter signed 4 p. quarto</unittitle><unitdate>dated December 3, 1786</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., to the care of Wm. Bedlow Esqr., New York. Relating to Loan Office matters, an alternation with the Treasury Board &amp;c. "Barber's situation is perhaps delicate from the prospect he has of continu</unittitle><unitdate>dated April 8, 1787</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Lansing, Abraham G., to Abraham Yates Junr, "The Election for representatives in Assembly has gone against us - Gansevoort, Ten Eyck, Gordon, Van Ingen, Van Orden, Younglove &amp; Sickles. Mrs. Robert Livingston of the Manor is also Dead". autograph letter si</unittitle><unitdate>dated June 4, 1737</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junior Esquire, New York. Refers to his brother John Lansing Jr. and Mr. Hamilton, "We have reports here that Mr. Paine is employed to write in favor of the British form of Government and that the system whi</unittitle><unitdate>dated August 26, 1767</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr., Poughkeepsie", I am of Opinion that the Measures adopted by Massachusetts Bay will give a tone to the determination of this Important Matter in our Legislature. It is roundly asserted here that </unittitle><unitdate>dated January 23, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., to the care of the postmaster, Poughkeepsie. "Politics are still at a stand. A report has been circulated here for some days informing that the Convention of Massachusetts had rejected the Const</unittitle><unitdate>dated January 31, 1786</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Lansing, Abraham G., copy of document addressed to Melancton Smith Esqr. Signed by John Lansing Junr., Jeremiah Van Rensselaer &amp; others, in autograph of Abraham G. Lansing. Requesting that a printer be sent up from New York with his press to look after th</unittitle><unitdate>March 1, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Lansing, Abraham G., to Abraham Yates Junr. The body of the letter refers to the desire of Lansing and his friends to have an unprejudiced printer in Albany, A postscript in handwriting of and signed by Henry Oothoudt. autograph letter signed 2 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>dated March 2, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr, to the house of Mr. Powers, Poughkeepsie. "Our Measures have hitherto a most favorable aspect and if we Continue our Exertions we have the greatest prospect of success". autograph letter signed 1</unittitle><unitdate>dated March 12, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. in Congress, New York. "The Majority of the Assembly is much greater than we had reason to expect. Communicate the agreeable information to his Excellency, and all our Friends". autograph letter </unittitle><unitdate>dated May 27, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr, in Congress, New York. Refers to the returns of the recent election &amp; the probability of a Majority in the State. "Should any System be proposed with you it will be well to forward a Sketch of it</unittitle><unitdate>dated June 1, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., New York. "It appears to be the opinion of all those whom I have conversed with that the Constitution wl'll be effectually amended previous to it adoption or that it will be Totally rejected", a</unittitle><unitdate>dated June 15, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. to the care of Willm. Bedlow Esqr., New York. Refers to the Constitutional Convention. "This Circumstance the Federal gentlemen will no doubt avail themselves of and procractinate the Business as</unittitle><unitdate>dated June 22, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr, to the care of William Bedlow Esqr., New York, An' interesting letter referring to the Convention. "The Federalists here plume themselves much on the Accession of New Hampshire. They can now give</unittitle><unitdate>dated June 29, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., New York. Referring to a quarrel in the city of Albany between the Federalists and the Antis caused by "our Friends and their Antagonists being heated with Liquor. I hope, if the Constitution is</unittitle><unitdate>dated July 9, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esq., New York, Referring to the Constitutional Convention, "Mr, Jones, it is said, is so much Intimidated by the Threats of the Federalists that he does not any more take an active part, M. Smith is l</unittitle><unitdate>dated July 20, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esquire, New York</unittitle></did><scopecontent><p>Refers to the plans of the Federalists in Albany for a celebration in honor of the adoption of the Constitution. "The Bill of Rights which is interwoven with the adoption is considered by the Majority of those to whom I have shewn it as a security against the Encroachments of the Gen., Government", Autograph letter signed 3 p. folio, dated Aug. 3, 1788.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Lansing, Abraham G., to William Barber, Original draft of letter. refers to the Commissioners of Forfeitures and also to Mr. Robert Barber, "a young gentleman who served some part of his time with Webster and in the Course of a Month I hope he will be ena</unittitle><unitdate>dated August 31, 1738</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Leonard, Enoch. An acknowledgment of his error as Inspector of Election in refusing Abm. Yates' vote &amp; agreeing to pay all the costs of the suit brought against him by Yates. A. D. S. 1 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>dated July 26, 1791</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>L'Hommedieu, Ezra, addressed to the Honble Abraham Yates Junr. Esquire, Albany. Refers to Yates' desire to obtain the position of Receiver of Taxes; mentions the acknowledgment of American Independence by Holland; also the death of Col, Lawrence near Char</unittitle><unitdate>August 2, 1782</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>L'Hommedieu, Ezra, addressed to The Honorable Abraham Yates Junr, Esq., Albany, favoured by Colo, Gonsavolt (Gansevoort), Referring to his demands for condensation for his services as Loan Officer, "The Prospects of Peace are not so favourable as they wer</unittitle><unitdate>October 28, 1782</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates, Esq., High Sheriff for the City &amp; County of Albany. Congratulating him on his appointment as Sheriff &amp; requesting that Patrick Magie be retained as "Jaylkeeper" autograph letter signed 1 p, folio, dat</unittitle><unitdate>October 7, 1754</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., High Sheriff of the City &amp; County of Albany. Regretting the appointment of Thos. Morrell as Jail-keeper. "As to Thos. Morrell prhaps you have not heard that I have promised him swiping the</unittitle><unitdate>October 21, 1754</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates, Esqr., High Sheriff of the County of Albany. Requesting him to come down to Claverack &amp; bring a "Writt" with him. autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Claverack</unittitle><unitdate>December 12, 1754</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. att Albany. "I am told that there is again a Committee to come from Boston to view and lay out lands, if not in my Manr at least in the neighbourhood. I hope you'll bring more friends along</unittitle><unitdate>January 31, 1755</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr. high Sheriff for the City &amp; County of Albany, "On my coming home I was informed that Some of my manor people took 3 new England men in my manor in arms &amp; Carryed them to your Goal by Virtue of a </unittitle><unitdate>March 3, 1755</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., High Sheriff for the City &amp; County of Albany. "With much difficulty I have at Last catched Josiah Loomis, the ringleader and first beginner of the troubles with the Boston Government, He i</unittitle><unitdate>April 14, 1755</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., High Sheriff for the City &amp; County of Albany. "Yours of the 25 ultimo was delivered me yesterday at Tackanick were I have been to turn out my rebellious Tenants &amp; pulled down their houses, which</unittitle><unitdate>May 2, 1755</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. "I am just ready to set out for Boston from whence I have reed 2 letters that my son Phillip is in a declining State. I am much pleased to hear that your Corporation received General Shirly in a Body &amp; tre</unittitle><unitdate>July 16, 1755</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esq., High Sheriff for the City &amp; County of Albany. "I find that you have sent Patrick down to Consult me. I have reason to believe that he does not intend to Execute that precept you mention", autogra</unittitle><unitdate>February 9, 1756</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr. att Albany, Relating to some escapes from Goal &amp; the best measures to take for the recapture of one called Shoemaker. autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston</unittitle><unitdate>March 31, 1756</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., High Sheriff of the City &amp; County of Albany. Relating to Judgments against Rebellious Tenants. "We have agreed to give the Govr. L 1800 pr. annum but he Refuses to take it &amp; insists on having L </unittitle><unitdate>October 20, 1756</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., High Sheriff of the City &amp; County of Albany. "I returned last night from New York &amp; shall be glad to see you here the beginning of the next week to Execute the Judgments". autograph letter signe</unittitle><unitdate>November 16, 1756</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., High Sheriff for the City &amp; County of Albany. "I wrote you on my arrival from New York &amp; desiring you to come down to Execute the Judgments of Court for turning my Rebellious Tenants out of poss</unittitle><unitdate>November 23, 1756</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., High Sheriff for the City &amp; County of Albany. "I have been threatened by Van Gelden's Sons to be murdered &amp; burnt down of which I gott an affidavit of a Sheffield man who heard them say it. I he</unittitle><unitdate>December 15, 1756</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., High Sheriff for the City &amp; County of Albany, "Mrs. Livingston told me that She heard the Rebels were again looking out &amp; marking out farms in my mannor". Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dat</unittitle><unitdate>April 14, 1757</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., High Sheriff for City &amp; county of Albany. Repeating the request of a former letter &amp; desiring him to come down without any Loss of time. autograph letter signed 1 p, folio, dated Manor Livingsto</unittitle><unitdate>April 27, 1757</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., High Sheriff att Albany. "Sir Charles told me I should apply to you. when ever any attempts were made to Settle or take possession of my Lands". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated M</unittitle><unitdate>May 9, 1757</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr., High Sheriff for the City &amp; County of Albany. Relating to the release from Goal of John Van Gelden &amp; his son "I fear he will come &amp; burn me down, or waylay &amp; kill me, at least he will join</unittitle><unitdate>May 15, 1757</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., High Sheriff for the City &amp; County of Albany. "I an on my Guard &amp; you'll I suppose not be surprised when you hear that I have Shott him, which I am determined to do the first time I see hi</unittitle><unitdate>May 18, 1757</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr, Sheriff of the County of Albany, Enclosing a Proclamation received from Mr. Banyar. autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated Manor Livingston</unittitle><unitdate>June 23, 1757</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Refers to Peter Dow's Illness &amp; to Col. Schuyler. "I often long to hear the news of your town &amp; of the army, which I most generally have Imperfect". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingst</unittitle><unitdate>July 3, 1757</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., High Sheriff of the City &amp; County of Albany. Refers to John Van Gelden's demand for the restitution of his horse, saddle, bridle, Guns &amp;c. which had bean taken from him when he was committ</unittitle><unitdate>July 6, 1757</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Interesting letter referring to the French &amp; Indian War. "Am heartily glad to hear that the Summer- set man of war has been so fortunate as to take two French Ships with 300 men &amp; L 89000 Sterling, but I s</unittitle><unitdate>July 19, 1757</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr, addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr, att Albany. Inquiring whether Mr. Bleeker intended to come down to run the line for him. autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston</unittitle><unitdate>November 5, 1757</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed, to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr., High Sheriff for the City &amp; County of Albany. Interesting letter relating to the expedition against Ticonderoga. "I see General Abercromby &amp; Lord! How have made application to Coll. Renss</unittitle><unitdate>February 17, 1758</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. "I have been at pickepsinck to assist my Couz's Robert &amp; Henry Livingston in their Election". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston</unittitle><unitdate>January 11, 1759</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Interacting letter relating to the politics of Albany. "Both parties have acted unpolitick &amp; without that honour &amp; Generousity with which Citysens ought to treat one the other, at all times &amp; more Especial</unittitle><unitdate>February 10, 1759</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr. High Sheriff of City &amp; County of Albany. Refers to the death of "our old friend, Capt. Winne. Lett me know what news you have &amp; where the greatest Strength of our Army is gone, Northward or Westw</unittitle><unitdate>June 8, 1759</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., High Sheriff for the City &amp; County of Albany. Interesting letter relating to the French &amp; Indian War. "I am in a Continual dread least I should hear of the French Fleets getting to Quebec before</unittitle><unitdate>June 15, 1759</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., High Sheriff for City &amp; County of Albany. Interesting letter relating to the French &amp; Indian War. "I beg you to write me the particulars of Niagara &amp; how it came about that Sir William, had the </unittitle><unitdate>August 6, 1759</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Interesting letter referring to Gen. Amherst, Sir. William Johnson, Gen. Wolfe, Admiral Rodney &amp; others. "In my opinion if we do not take Canada we shall gitt very little by this war". autograph letter sig</unittitle><unitdate>August 30, 1759</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr, att Albany. "I have seen the article of Surrender of Quebec in our papers, which; are also Extraordinary and moth of a piece with those of Gardaloupe, neither of which please me. I do not t</unittitle><unitdate>November 24, 1759</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. att Albany, Refers to his lot in the "Sarightoga Pattent". "The French officers make a long tarry on our frontiers, provisions are more plenty there then at Canada". Autograph letter 6. 1 p</unittitle><unitdate>January 3, 1760</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr, Referring to Yates having been removed from office by his enemies, "They now begin with me, the Great &amp; mighty Coll, has seared upon my horses &amp; Sleds". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livi</unittitle><unitdate>January 24, 1760</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. "God Grant we may Soon take all Canada &amp; keep it while the world Stands, that we may be relieved from Sundry pette Tyrants who rule with a Rod of Iron the best Subjects the King of Great Brittain has in al</unittitle><unitdate>February 8, 1760</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Refers to the Albany Library. "God Grant us Success that the Enemy may be obliged to Sue for a peace before the End of this year". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston</unittitle><unitdate>February 29, 1760</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr. att Albany, Very interesting letter containing war news, "I heard that the French have Raised the Siege of Quebec on the appearance of our fleet, I shall order a good fat Oxen to be brought</unittitle><unitdate>May 30, 1760</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates Junr., Merchant in Albany. Referring to the Albany election, certain lands in Saratoga Patent, making mention of Col, Bradstreet, the Bleeckers, Ten Rroecks and De Ridders, &amp; closing; as follows: -</unittitle><unitdate>July 17, 1760</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. att Albany, Refers to the damage to crops paused by heavy rains all the way from Fishkill up to Albany. "I expect our Army is now in motion. This is a time we ought above all others to humb</unittitle><unitdate>August 11, 1760</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates Junr. att Albany. Refers to the good news that "our Armies are now in possession of all Canada". Also mentions Yates' desire to again obtain the office of Sheriff. autograph letter signed 1 p. foli</unittitle><unitdate>September 3, 1760</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr. att Albany. "I have this day, wrote to my Brother Philip &amp; William to wate on his Honr. the President and to desire the favour of him in my name to appoint you Sheriff for the Ensuing year". auto</unittitle><unitdate>September 9, 1760</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates Junr., Merchant In Albany. "I Long to hear what voyages your Albany Gentlemen have made to Canada. I also want to know how the Troops are to be disposed of now the war is at an End in our- Quarter"</unittitle><unitdate>October 13, 1760</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr. att Albany. Refers to the sale of lands in the Saratoga Patent by the Bleeckers, Mr. Ten 'Broeck &amp; Schuyler &amp; "your old uncle Killiaen". "I imagine your City must enlarge that way, while no</unittitle><unitdate>November 7, 1760</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esq, att Albany. "But how your uncle Killiaen will sell any I am at a loss to know, as I heard sometime ago that there was some difficulty in his Tittle". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Mano</unittitle><unitdate>November 13, 1760</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr. addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. att Albany. Refers to Killiaen De Ridder's title to lands in the Saratoga Patent. "I hear It hinted from New York that we are going to have an expedition this winter to the Mississippi - tha</unittitle><unitdate>December 10, 1760</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr, In Albany, Refers to a petition addressed by the Corporation of the City of Albany to "the President &amp; Council". "I Congratulate you on the Victory Lately gained by the King of Prussia, thi</unittitle><unitdate>January 22, 1761</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Referring to the election in Albany &amp; mentioning various candidates, "If you are Inclinable to Sett up with Mr. Abraham Ten Broeck, whom I Look upon to be without any flattery the two best Qualifyed in you</unittitle><unitdate>February 4, 1761</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Referring to the coming Election &amp; the difference of opinion existing between Yates &amp; Ten Broeck, Mentions Sir William Johnson, "who undoubtedly has great Interest". "As for my part while my friends are so</unittitle><unitdate>February 6, 1761</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. att Albany</unittitle></did><scopecontent><p>Refers to Yates' standing for the coming Election. "The Camps will not move to an Election without being payed for their time at 4 o/ pr. man. The Gentlemen of the other Side have wrote me for my Interest but have not had opportunity to answer them. Sir William I find has, which by the by is not so very agreeable to them". Autograph letter signed 2 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston, Feb. 8, 1761.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr. unsigned draft of letter in his autograph. "As my friend Mr. Ab. Yates wrote me the 4 Current that he Intended to Stand Candidate &amp; desired my Interest I could not refuse him". This draft is a copy of a letter sent by Livingston </unittitle><unitdate>February 8, 1761</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates Junr., Merchant att Albany, Refers to dishonorable methods used at Elections. "I see you are like to have new Troubles upon your Corporation for encroachments by the Township of Schenectady". autog</unittitle><unitdate>February 16, 1761</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., Addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates Junr., Merchant att Albany. Refers to Yates failure at the recent Election. "You have now experienced what dependence there is on that frail Creature Called man. I hope however. you have not paid t</unittitle><unitdate>March 26, 1761</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Refers to Yates' desire to be appointed Sheriff on the death of the person, then holding that office. autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston</unittitle><unitdate>May 11, 1761</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Mr. James Stevenson, Merchant In Albany. "I have ordered my young man to go up with the pittejagoe &amp; to Carry as much bar Iron: for you as it will conveniently load". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manor </unittitle><unitdate>July 9, 1761</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esq. in Albany. Refers to Mr. Stevenson some business with the Sheriff. "As head Quarters is now in your City, doubtless you have all the news Running, as I here am barren must Entreat you to Communica</unittitle><unitdate>July 21, 1761</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esq. att Albany. "I was in great hopes that after the Reduction of all Canada arbitrary power and all other Illegal proceedings by the Gentlemen of the army would have been at an end. You tell me a pie</unittitle><unitdate>July 28, 1761</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esq. att Albany, Refers to the disposition of the troops then stationed on Staten Island; to the War on the Continent; mentions Col, Grant, sir William Johnson &amp; Gen. Monckton. "I have not heard that a</unittitle><unitdate>August 5, 1761</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, att Albany, Wishes Hendrick Bogart to come down to put a new bottom in his Sloop. "The fleet is Saild I heard for Barbados their to make the randevous for getherlng the whole fleet &amp; army togethe</unittitle><unitdate>December 2, 1761</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., attorney at law In Albany. An interesting letter relating to affairs in Germany, Spain, Denmark, Russia &amp;c.; also commenting on domestic news. "By the Speach of his Honr., to the Assembly </unittitle><unitdate>December 8, 1761</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston., Robert, Junr, addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., Attorney at Law In Albany, Referring to a "white Seader Swamp" &amp; enclosing a letter of Yates' relating to Van Bergen's land. autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston</unittitle><unitdate>February 8, 1762</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., attorney at Law in Albany. Referring to the unpleasant feeling existing between the late &amp; present Mayors &amp; mentioning the sale of lots in the Saratoga Patent. autograph letter signed 3 p.</unittitle><unitdate>March 4, 1762</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., attorney at Law In Albany. Mentions Killiaan De Ridder, Mr, Lydius, Mr. Stevenson &amp; Mr. Silvester. "A Spanish War seems to threaten &amp; prhaps we are on the Eve of it. It's true we are at pr</unittitle><unitdate>March 13, 1762</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Attorney at Law In Albany, Refers to the request of the English Presbyterians for a meeting-house, where the "Grenary" now stands. "I Congratulate you on the Reduction of Martinico, this i</unittitle><unitdate>April 19, 1752</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Attorney at Law In Albany. "I want to hear how our army at Martinico is to be disposed of for the Summer Season and what other Expeditions we are to undertake". autograph letter signed 1 p</unittitle><unitdate>May 8, 1762</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. att Albany. Referring to trouble in the church &amp; mentioning the birth of a child in Yates' family. "I am just going to a bon Fire I have Caused to be Erected as a testimony of our Joy on th</unittitle><unitdate>September 13, 1762</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr, Referring to Col, Van Rensselaer 's meeting with his tenants and the validity of their leases. Also mentions Mr, Jeremiah Van Rensselaer, autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston</unittitle><unitdate>December 2, 1762</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Loan Office Endorsed: "Return for October, 1782"</unittitle><physdesc>copy. D. 2 p. quarto</physdesc></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Lott, Abraham, to The Honorable Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. of the Senate at Poughkeepsie. Refers to his confinement in Goal &amp; a Memorial which he wished to have laid before the Legislature. autograph letter signed 1 p folio, dated New York Goal</unittitle><unitdate>January 22, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Low, Isaac (Chairman), to Mr. Jacob Lansingh, Chairman of the Committee of the City and County of Albany. Relating to some goods forwarded to Mr. Abraham Schuyler &amp; Mr. - Andrew McFarlin. autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>December 15, 1774</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>McCall, J, (Secretary), to Abraham Yates Esqr., Commissioner of the C. L. O. for the State of New York. Concerning a Bill of Exchange. L. R. 1 p. quarto, dated Office of Finance</unittitle><unitdate>October 23, 1732</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>McKay, Alexander, addressed to Mr, Abraham Yates Esqr. Attorney at Law in Albany. His bill against Jno. McFall for the amount of which he brings suit. D. S. 1 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>dated February 1765</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>McKerlie, John. His affidavit concerning Ensign Howard. "The people seem to be suspicious of General Schuyler and his proceedings and that they were also suspicious that the Provisions going up were for the use of the King's Troops". D. S. 1 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>dated May 18, 1776</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Metcalfe, George. Acknowledgment of himself as author of an article in the Federal Herald Feb, 18, 1788. derogatory to Abraham Yates Junr. &amp; admitting the falseness of the same. Also signed by Thos, Q. Witbeck &amp; Abm, Reynolds. A. D. S. 1 p. folio, dated A</unittitle><unitdate>April 25, 1789</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Milligan, James (Compt. of the Treasury), copy of document sent to The Honorable The Board of Treasury. Refers to the settlement of Abraham Yates Junr's accounts as Loan Officer. 4 p. large folio, dated Camp- troller's Office</unittitle><unitdate>December 9, 1786</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Mohawney, John, to Abraham Yates Junr. Esq., Albany. An order to pay to Cornelius Glen the amount due him. Signed by Matthew Visscher, Abraham Yates Junr. &amp; Cornelius Glen. D. signed by his mark, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>September 30, 1772</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Morris, Robert, to his Excellency The Governor &amp; Commander in Chief of the State of New York. Concerning the account of the United States against the State of New York. "Your Excellency must be sensible of the Impracticability of carrying on the War unles</unittitle><unitdate>July 16, 1781</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Morris, Robert, to Governor Clinton. Concerning the account against the State of New York for specific supplies &amp; asking information of Gov. Clinton on various points. autograph letter signed 5 p. folio, dated Philadelphia</unittitle><unitdate>July 25, 1781</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Morris, Robert, probably addressed to Gov. Clinton, Pointing out the erroneous ideas held by Americans as to the financial aid given by France &amp; Spain &amp; Holland to the United States. "Not a single State has acknowledged our Independence except France". Pa</unittitle><unitdate>October 19, 1731</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Morris, Robert (probably), part of a letter presumably sent by Morris either to the President of Congress or the Governor of the State of New York, explaining at length his scheme for funding the national debt. D. 24 p. quarto, dated Office of Finance</unittitle><unitdate>July 29, 1782</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Morris, Robert. copy of Document to the Commissioners for Settling Accounts of the States. Copy made by Wm. Barber. The whole is endorsed: - "Queres. proposed by the Auditors appointed to settle the Accts. of the States of Maryland &amp; New Jersey with the </unittitle><unitdate>September 7, 1782</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Morris, Robert, to Abraham Yates Esq., Loan Officer for New York, "You will be pleased to transmit me all the Bills of Exchange now in your Office". L. S. 1 p. quarto, dated Office of Finance</unittitle><unitdate>September 9, 1782</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Morris, Robert, to Abraham Yates Junr. Esquire, Contl. Loan Officer for the State of New York. "You will receive from the Treasurer of the United States a Discharge for the Bill of Exchange therein mentioned". L. S. 1 p. quarto, dated Office of Finance</unittitle><unitdate>October 23, 1782</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Morris, Robert, to Abraham Yates Esqr., Loan Officer of the State of New York at Albany. "As to the request you make of Money I am very sorry to say that it is not in my Power to comply with it". L. S. 2 p. quarto, dated Office of Finance</unittitle><unitdate>November 29, 1782</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Murray, Joseph addressed to William Corry Esquire, Attorney at Law in Albany. Relating to various legal cases. L. S. 2 p. folio, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>August 2, 1756</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Oothoudt, Henry, addressed to Honorable Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. &amp; Congress, New York. "On the 17th the Convention met - 53 Members present. The Chancellor opened with a long Oration - Moved a Resolution that the Proposed plan of Government be Discussed </unittitle><unitdate>June 21, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Oothoudt, Henry, addressed to Honorable Abraham Yates Junr. in Congress, New York, "Yesterday we Proceeded to the Consideration of the first Clause of the 8th Section of the first Article". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Poughkeepsie</unittitle><unitdate>June 27, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Osgood, Samuel; Livingston, Walter; Lee, Arthur, Addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr., New York. "It is our Duty to remind you that until you have taken the Usual Oath of Office we cannot Consider you as a Commissioner of the Loan Office under the Ordin</unittitle><unitdate>March 1, 1786</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Osgood, Samuel; Livingston, Walter; Lee, Arthur. To Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. Transmitting a Resolve of Congress in reference to the Oath of Office &amp; returning the Oath left by Yates at the office; of the Board of Treasury. L. S. 2 p. quarto, dated Board </unittitle><unitdate>dated March 3, 1786</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Petry, William; Frank, John; Fox, Friedenrich. Their appraisal of certain lands forfeited by John Tompson, Endorsed: - "The within supposed to have been sold by Gen, Gansevoort &amp; Jeremiah Van Rensselaer". D. S. 1 p. quarto, dated Johnstown</unittitle><unitdate>February 10, 1785</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Political Broadside - Announcement "To the Electors of the State of New York". Requesting the electors to support Jay and Van Rensselaer and containing the names of over 80 prominent; citizens of New York. Double page printed folio</unittitle><unitdate>dated February 10, 1795</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Rogers, John, addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates, Attorney at Law in Albany, Asking information regarding some case at law. autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>September 24, 1768</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Schuyler, Pieter (Mayor of Albany). A reply to Oom. Godevridus van Dell's application -in regard to the highway. A. D. S. 2 p. folio, dated</unittitle><unitdate>December 4, 1688</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Schuyler, Philip; Ten Broeck, Abraham; Livingston, Peter R. Addressed to Abraham Yates Esq., Chairman of the Committee of Correspondence, Albany. Interesting letter relative to Important decisions of the House of Assembly. "You will at one glance perceive</unittitle><unitdate>February 25, 1774</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Silvester, Peter. Bill of costs in suit of Janneke Van Hoosen against Dirck Van Derheyden, receipted by Silvester as attorney for Defendant. D. S. 1 p. quarto</unittitle><unitdate>dated May 19, 1767</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Silvester, Peter, addressed to The Honble Abraham Yates Esqr., New York, Concerning the overpayment of a certain Mr. Beache. A L. S. 1 p. folio dated Kinderhook</unittitle><unitdate>June 19, 1787</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Six Nations Endorsed: "Answer of the Six Nations to the Speech of the 12 United Colonies 1775"</unittitle></did><scopecontent><p>Document 3 p. quarto, part of it in the autograph of Abm. Yates Junr. Also, Document, 1 p, quarto, endorsed: - "Speech to the Indiana when they rec'd the Presents.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Smith, Melancton, addressed to The Honl. Abraham Yates Junr. Esq., Poughkeepsie. "Report here said that you was defunct and that your funeral had been solemnized with great pomp. We have nothing authentic from the Convention of Massachusetts. The decision</unittitle><unitdate>January 23, 1968</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Smith, Melancton, addressed to The Honl. Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Poughkeepsie refers to the adoption of the Constitution. "He advises that the Sun granted as a donation should be acknowledged as a debt, and included in the Obligations given to the Cour</unittitle><unitdate>January 28, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Smith, William, addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., in Albany. Refers to his serious illness and sending remembrances to his friends in Albany. autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manr. St. George</unittitle><unitdate>July 18, 1786</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Smith, William, to Abraham Yates Esqr. Refers to the New Constitution. "It Strikes me with amusement that Good Whigs who Suffered and underwent what they Did Should turn tall too". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manr. St. George</unittitle><unitdate>June 12, 1783</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Swart, Dirck, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. at Albany. Referring to 5 Plates sent up to Yates by Esq. Fonda's Sloop. Also Bill for same, oblong strip in Dirck Swart's autograph. autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated Manor Livingston</unittitle><unitdate>March 18, 1756</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Taylor, William, addressed to Mr. Ome La Grange Living at the Hellebargh. Mentioning his father's will &amp; advising him to subject Ary La Grange to a strict cross-questioning regarding the same, autograph letter signed 1 p. folio dated Hellebargh</unittitle><unitdate>March 23, 1768</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Ten Broeck, Abraham (Chairman). Abraham Yates Junr's license for six years to use the books of the Albany Library. Also signed by James Van Ingen, Treasurer. D. S. 1 small square printed from, dated</unittitle><unitdate>April 19, 1793</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Ten Broeck, Abraham, Printed Broadside, recommending Gen, Philip Schuyler as a Candidate for the vacant seat of a Member of Senate. Signed by Abm, Ten Broeck as Chairman. '1 p. folio, dated In Committee Albany</unittitle><unitdate>April 2, 1795</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Ten Broeck, Dirck, addressed to the Honbl Abraham Yates Junr. Esquire, Albany, Referring to some document which he enclosed in the letter. autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>June 16, 1791</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Ten Broeck, Dirck, to the Honbl, Abm, Yates Junr. Esqr. An acknowledgment of his error in Judgment as an Inspector of Election in not allowing Abraham Yates' suffrage. A. D. S. 2 p. folio, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>June 16, 1791</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Ten Broeck, Dirck. An acknowledgment of his error in refusing Yates 'vote &amp; agreeing to pay all the costs of the suit brought against him by Yates. A. D. S. 1 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>dated July 25, 1791</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Ten Eyck, Henry, Junr. His receipt for 42 pounds 6 shillings. D. S. 2 p. quarto</unittitle><unitdate>dated May 14, 1771</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Ten Eyck, Jacob C. (Judge). Affidavit of Christian Ehl in his case against Thomas Winn. D. S. 1 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>dated May 25, 1765</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Ten Eyck, John (Recorder). Bill of costs in the suit of Andries Wies against Sybrant G. Van Schaick. D. S. 1 small piece, no date, about</unittitle><unitdate>1754 (?)</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Van Eps, John E., addressed to Mr. Abrun Yates, attorney at Lew at Albany, to the care of Joseph Yates at Schonechdadie. Mentions Andries Gardinier and his brother Jacob, autograph letter signed in Dutch, 1 p. folio, dated Cagenuwaga</unittitle><unitdate>May 22, 1760</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Van Rensselaer, Jeremiah, addressed to Robert Yates Esqr., Attorney at Law, Albany. Asking him to arrest immediately one Jacob of Cloverack. "John McCombes has Settled with me". autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>September 9, 1764</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Van Renssealaer, Jeremiah, to Abraham Yates Junr. "The Montgomery Delegates are Expected in town this Evening. Judge Oothoudt, the Mayor and such others as May be Ready Embark this Evening With Capt. Van Wosrt for Poughkeepsie. autograph letter signed 1 p</unittitle><unitdate>June 13, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Van Rensselaer, Stephen. Receipt given Abraham Yates Junr D. S. 1 p. folio in autograph of &amp; also signed by Peter W. Yales</unittitle><unitdate>dated September 17, 1764</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Van Schaick, Wessel, Two Bills of Exchange drawn on Messrs. Sargent Chambers &amp; Co., Merchants to London, in favor of him &amp; signed by Reade &amp; Yates. D. 1 p. quarto, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>August 24, 1770</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Visscher, Matthew, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. An interesting letter, narrating the experiences of Maj. Bigelow, who was sent with a flag. from, our Army to the Commander of the British Troop We were mads to believe that the Americans were mean</unittitle><unitdate>August 19, 1776</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Visscher, Matthew, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Kingston. Interesting letter referring to the condition of Schoharie, mentioning Gen. Arnold as "gone to the westward" &amp; repeating Col. Willett's Interesting description of affaire at Fort Schuyle</unittitle><unitdate>August 15, 1777</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Visscher, Matthew, to Abraham Yates Esq. Refers to a Petition of George G. Klock's &amp; touches upon many political points. "Does not the Confederation expressly declare that Delegates shall be annually appointed, and take their Seats in Congress on the firs</unittitle><unitdate>dated March 6, 1786</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Visscher, Matthew, addressed to Ab. Yates Junr., John McKesson and Melancton Smith esqr., New York. "The Antifederalists had a Majority in every District except the City of Albany". autograph letter signed 2 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>dated May 30, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Wendell, Evert draft of Indenture between him- And Hendrick Wendell of Sinckchaick, of the one part, and John Johannis Fonda, son of Susanna, one of the daughters of Abm. Wendell dec'd, of the Colony of Rensselaer Wyck, of the other part. Document, part </unittitle><unitdate>dated June 1767</unitdate><physdesc><extent>3 pages folio</extent></physdesc></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Wendell, Harmanus. Draft of his Will. Signed by Jacob Pruyn, John Ja. Lansingh &amp; Pet. Silvester as witnesses. D. S. 2 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>dated April 18, 1757</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Wendell, Harmanus. Memorial addressed by Harmanus Wendell, Lucas Van Veghten &amp; another to Sir Jeffery Amherst, Commander in Chief of all his Majesties forces in America, requesting a Pass to go from Albany to Montreal, Draft of Document in autograph of Ab</unittitle><unitdate>dated January 23, 1762</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Wendell, Harmanus. Draft of his Will, part of it in the autograph of Abraham Yates Junr. D. 4 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>dated May 25, 1769</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Wendell, Harmanue H., addressed to his father, "Harmanus Wendell, Merchant in Albany "Mr. John Fry telse me he has been Drunk For Six Weeks upon a Stretch and is So Every Day". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Schenectady</unittitle><unitdate>January 16, 1762</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Wendell, Henry I, addressed to Abraham Yates Esq., Sheriff In Albany</unittitle></did><scopecontent><p>"Lord How has Ordered me Immediately to Proceed With my Company and Complete it upon the Mohawk River". Autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated Albany, April 4, 1758.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Werth, Johan Jacob, Addressed to Mstr. Abraham Yates, Scheriff living in Albany. Reminding him of his promise to send the under-sheriff to Schoharie. autograph letter signed in Dutch, 1 p. folio, dated Schocharie</unittitle><unitdate>April 9, 1757</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Whitney, Thomas, addressed to Abraham Yates Esq, at Albany. Asking him to "take Cear of two "Rites". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated' Clouvriack</unittitle><unitdate>October 6, 1760</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Whitney, Thomas, to Abraham Yates Junr. Telling him. he had settled his Action with Robert Noble. autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Clouvarieck</unittitle><unitdate>October 29, 1760</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Williston, John, addressed to Mr. Yates att Albany, Atorney att Law. Asking advice as to how he should proceed in his action with Parsons. autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated Springfield</unittitle><unitdate>July 18, 1764</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Winn, John, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. Asking him. to call on him as soon as possible to give him advice regarding action toward his creditors. autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Albany City Hall</unittitle><unitdate>May 8, 1773</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Winne Anthonoy addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates at Albany, Requesting him to collect from Peter Brandt the money ha was owing Winne for a load of hay. autograph letter signed 1 p. small quarto, dated Cosakkey</unittitle><unitdate>September 5, 1769</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Winne, Jellis. His Bill against Abm. Yates Junr., the same being receipted July 10, 1765. A. D. S. in Dutch, 1 p. small quarto</unittitle><unitdate>dated January 1765</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter In his autograph to - -. Relative to the sale of land. autograph letter signed 2 p. folio, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>October 29, 1760</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham; Junr., draft of letter in his autograph to Robert Livingston Junr. Long interesting letter relating to the Elections in Albany, Mentions Abraham Ten Broeck's dishonorable conduct toward Yates, Sir Willian Johnson's influence &amp;c. 6 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>dated February 16, 1761</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr, Endorsed: - "A. Yates' Junrs. observation on Limits of the City 1761" "We are apprehensive that we will be obliged to contend with this Inhabitants of Schenectady about the Bounds and Jurisdiction of our City". D. 4 p. folio, dated A</unittitle><unitdate>February 21, 1761</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter in his autograph to Robert Livingston Junr, Refers to the division of a Patent "that Joins on the Half noon. "Anthony Van Schayck Brake the chain after some Discourse about the, Consequences of Stepping the Commissio</unittitle><unitdate>dated September 27, 1762</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter in his autograph to Samuel Dunham. Relative to his suit with Thomas Smith Junr. of Charles Town, South Carolina. 1 p. quarto</unittitle><unitdate>dated September 13, 1764</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr. His affidavit relative to the head of a wolf brought before him by Michael Lansing A. D. S. l small square</unittitle><unitdate>dated November 4, 1766</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter in his autograph to Alexander McKay. Relative to his various legal suits. 2 p. quarto, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>February 8, 1768</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed to Mr. Hyde, Son of Capt. Hide, at Sarachtoge, Behind Walran Cluto. Requesting him to come down, get his Lease &amp; pay the Debt which his father owed. L. S. 1 p. quarto, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>April 11 1769</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr. to Saml. Jones Esqr. in behalf of Corporation Requesting his opinion in a case. Autograph letter, draft of</unittitle><unitdate>dated February 3, 1771</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham Junr. Relating to the first settlement of Albany. "I now propose to add the reasons that induces me to think that the West India Company by Virtue of their Grant from the States of Holland had no right to the Possessions, Commons &amp;c of the </unittitle><unitdate>March 19, 1771</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr. Complaint made by John Mohawney, through Abraham Yates, his attorney, against Benjamin Springer for failure to pay him various sums of money borrowed from said Mohawney.. D. 3 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>dated June 1772</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr. draft of letter in his autograph. Endorsed "to Rt Yates". (Robert Yates). Concerning the sale of some wins. Small square piece, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>June 10, 1776</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr. addressed to the Committee of Albany</unittitle></did><scopecontent><p>Also signed by Mat. Adgate &amp; Jno. J. Bleecker. "Yesterday a Committee was appointed to draw up a Resolve- to Put you under a Peremptory Rule to furnish the Congress with your Proceedings against Abm. Cuyler, Henry Cuyler, John Duncan, Stephan De Lancey, Benj. Hilton &amp; John Monier". D. S. 1 p. folio, dated July 26, 1776. Yates Abraham Junr. draft of constitution N. Y. [1777] (See p. 19 of this list) Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter in his autograph, to James Duane Esq. Refers to his disappointment in not being appointed Receiver of Taxes. "I have had the Loan Office over three years without a Copper in pay". 2 p. folio, dated Albany, Sept. 7 1782.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr., to The Honble Robert Morris Esq., Superintendent of Finance. Refers to a Bill of Exchange which he will transmit with the Returns for the present month. Draft of letter, 1 p. quarto, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>September 21, 1782</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter to the Honble Robert Morris Esq., Superintendent of Finance;. Transmitting a Return for the Month of Sept. and also a Bill of Exchange. 1 p. small quarto, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>October 4, 1792</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter in his autograph to the Hon'bl James Duane &amp; Ezra L'Hommedieu</unittitle></did><scopecontent><p>An interesting letter giving the substance of a conversation with Col. Hamilton. "I told him I thought the Financier had too much Power already and that Congress had better curtail him - but I thought Congress could not now take it up as he had done Congress such Essential service". 3 p. quarto, dated Albany, Oct. 19, 1782.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr. draft of letter to. the Honbl. Robert Morris Esq., Superintendent of Finance, Philadelphia. "I am exposed to Inconveniences by having devoted three whole Years to Service of the public for which I have not hitherto with repeated Soli</unittitle><unitdate>November 4, 1782</unitdate></did><scopecontent><p>Also another copy of the same in a different handwriting. 2 p. folio.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of his letter to Judge David Howell, Refers to the pamphlets of Dr. Price &amp; the Abbe De Mably &amp; the five points discussed in them, relative to the dangers threatening the Government. 2 p. quarto, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>August 29, 1785</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Abraham G. Lansing (probably), "I am making ready to Dine at the Gover's where I expect to see Coll, Monson and some others that probably will give me information of the Loan office". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio dated New </unittitle><unitdate>February 1, 1786</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed to Abm. G. Lansing, Post Master, Albany. Mentions Duer, Bancker, Osgood- &amp; refers to the Oath of Office which he was required to take. autograph letter signed 2 p. folio, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>March 1, 1786</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr. draft of letter In his autograph &amp; signed by him, to William Smith, Long Island. Expressing sympathy on account of his illness &amp; extending an invitation to himself &amp; wife to make a visit in Albany. 2 p. quarto, dated Albany</unittitle><unitdate>July 27, 1786</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr. draft of letter In his autograph to - -, Refers to canvassing the voices for Senator. 1 p. folio, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>June 2, 1787</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Abraham G. Lansing. "Antifederal Business is Carried on in this County with spirit. New York they are all in a panic with the adoption of Massachusetts". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Poughkeepsie</unittitle><unitdate>February 28, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Munr., to Abraham G. Lansing. Relating to politics. "They Honour me with being at the head of that party and to that end have been all the scurrilous publications". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Senate Room, Poughkeepsie</unittitle><unitdate>March 14, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Abraham G. Lansing. "Wether We will breaks up this week and when is made uncertain by Mr. Duane, Lawrence and Van Der Bilt arrived here (it is said) for the express purpose of Carrying the Legislator to New York". autograph lette</unittitle><unitdate>March 18, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr, addressed to Abm, G. Lansing Esq, Albany. Reports a conversation held with Col. Hamilton. "I told him rather than to adopt the Constitution I would risk a government of Jew, Turk or Infidle. I told him the government that were agreea</unittitle><unitdate>May 28, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Abraham &amp;. Lansing, Refers to the Assembly Election &amp; the hopes of the Federalists for the adoption of the Constitution. autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>June 1, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed to Abraham G. Lansing Esq., Post Officer, Albany. Refers to the adoption of the Constitution. "The members from this place seem determined not to adopt (without previous amendments) tho all the others should. What steps th</unittitle><unitdate>June 15, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr. addressed to Abm. G, Lansing Esq., Post Master, Albany. Refers to his suit against Claxton, the printer, &amp; gives some of his ideas in regard to the education of children. autograph letter signed 2 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>June 23, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed to Abraham G. Lansing Esq., Albany. "Whilst I am writing advise is brought that New Hampshire had adopted the New Constitution which bread such an inattention to the Business the Southern Members to write letters to Virgin</unittitle><unitdate>June 25, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr., 2 drafts of letter in his autograph to the Governor. Refers to the news from New Hampshire &amp; the Loan from Holland. "L'Hommedieu last Monday mentioned that he had form a strong Federal (Dr. Tillotson) that the Anties went upon a sup</unittitle><unitdate>June 27, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed to Abraham G. Lansing, Post Master, Albany. "It appears that the Anties are neither to be frowned or flattered out of their opinion". Also refers to the lean made in Holland &amp; the proposal to make a new loan. Autograph let</unittitle><unitdate>June 29, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr., document, part of it in his autograph. Endorsed: -"Minuter of the Convention which formed the Constitution of the State of New York". Refers to the manner of carrying on elections for Senators &amp;c.; the duties of the Governor &amp; other</unittitle><unitdate>undated [1777]</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr. A statement of his reasons for voting for the new Constitution, tho he was opposed to it in principle. Also, an acknowledgment of the receipt of the above declaration, signed by Ezra L'Hommedieu, Egbert Benson &amp; Alexander Hamilton. A</unittitle><unitdate>dated August 8, 1788</unitdate></did><scopecontent><p>Also, Document in autograph of Abraham Yates Junr., a. copy of the above. 2 p. quarto.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr. Also signed by John H. Cook &amp; John De Wandelaer as witnesses. In autograph of Abm. G. Lansing. William Angell's warrant of Attorney to Abraham G. Lansing. Also, Document signed by Abraham Yates Junr., John H. Cook &amp; John De Wandelaer</unittitle><unitdate>dated February 25, 1791</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter, to Aaron Burr This draft was apparentlysent to Robert Yates Esq, for his approval before sending the letter to Burr. Refers to the case against Mr. Ten Broeck, for which Burr was Yates' attorney, 2 p. quarto, dated </unittitle><unitdate>April 24, 1791</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr. draft letter to Dirck Ten Broeck Esq, Relative to the withdrawal of Yates' suit against Ten Broeck. "As the Injury is of a public as well as private nature It is my intention Directly to publish the Certificate". 1. quarto, dated Alb</unittitle><unitdate>June 18, 1791</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Abraham, Junr. (Mayor) An Act of the Corporation, of the City of Albany. "allowing &amp; permitting a Ferry Stairs to be erected in the Wharf opposite to Mark Lane". D. S. 1 p. folio, dated in Common Council</unittitle><unitdate>June 21, 1793</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Christopher P., addressed to Abraham Yates Esq. and in his absence to Matthew Viescher Esq. in Albany. Interesting letter asking assistance from the Albany Committee. "We have just recd. Intelligence by Express from Oneida that a large Body of Indi</unittitle><unitdate>June 8, 1776</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Christopher P., addressed to Henry Glen Esq., A. D. Q. M. Genl. Schenectady. Declining to accept a seat in either House of the Legislature for family reasons, "As to Major Frey I know his Sentiments on the Subject so well that I am well convinced h</unittitle><unitdate>April 7, 1781</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Christopher P. addressed to the Hon. Abraham Yates Esq. in Congress, New York. Interesting letter in relation, to the adoption of the Constitution. The Federalists appear much elated by the adoption of the Constitution in N. Hampshire. We are got t</unittitle><unitdate>June 27, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Christopher P., addressed to Hon. Abraham Yates Esquire, New York. Interesting letter referring to a heated argument between Mr. Lansing and Mr. Hamilton, in the Constitutional Convention, on the necessity of the existence of the State governments </unittitle><unitdate>June 30, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Christopher P., addressed to Mr. John Pourteous, Referring to three Judgments against some small estates. A. L, S, 1 p. quarto</unittitle><unitdate>dated August 14, 1791</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Joseph C. (Governor), addressed to Christopher Y. Lansing Esquire, Albany, Subscribing for 500 shares of stock of the Commercial Bank</unittitle><physdesc><extent>1 page quarto</extent></physdesc></did><scopecontent><p>L. S. 1 p. quarto, dated Schenectady, May 29, 1825.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Peter, Document signed by him, Johannis Saml. Pruyn, Matthew Visscher, Christopher P. Yates &amp; others. Indenture &amp; Copy of Mortgage Bond of house and lot in the second ward of the city of Albany. 5 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>dated November 16, 1767</unitdate><unitdate>dated May 30, 1769</unitdate><unitdate>dated April 10, 1776</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Peter W,  addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Leonard Gansevoort &amp; John D. P. Ten Eyck, Esquires, Pokeepsy, Referring to a petition presented to the Legislature by Mary Elmendorph. Autograph letter signed 2 p. folio, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>January 21, 1788</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Richard. Order on Messrs. Sargent Chambers &amp; Co. of London to pay one hundred pounds to Evert Bancker, Endorsed by Evert Bancker. A. D. S. oblong strip, dated New York</unittitle><unitdate>March 23, 1774</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Robert, Complaint of Thomas Winn, through Robert Yates, his attorney, against Christian Alli for selling him a bay stallion under false pretences and asking damages to the extent of 18 pounds. D. 2 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>dated January, 1767</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Robert, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Chairman of the Committee, Albany. Introducing Col. Flemming, "a gentleman appointed by this Congress adjutant General to the Army under the Command of General Schuyler". autograph letter signed 1 p. </unittitle><unitdate>September 6, 1775</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Robert Intersting paper giving extracts from the resolves of the Committee of Safety for the State of New York in reference to the purchase of wheat for the use of the Continental Army and the exemption of certain coopers from militia duty. D. S. 2</unittitle><unitdate>October 29, 1776</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Robert, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Member of Congress at New York. Refers to the Philadelphia Convention. "Additional Rules have since been entered into, one of which strictly prohibits the communication of its business until the final</unittitle><unitdate>June 1, 1787</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Robert. Ordering the Sheriff to discharge from custody Thomas Lewis Spotten &amp; James Spotten of the town of Lansingburg. 3 p. large folio</unittitle><unitdate>dated November 5, 1790</unitdate></did></c02><c02 level="file"><did><unittitle>Yates, Robert, Discharge of Joseph Tobias, who had been confined in the Albany jail. D. S. 2 p. folio</unittitle><unitdate>dated March 3, 1791</unitdate></did></c02></c01></dsc></archdesc>
</ead>
