<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://uri.nypl.org/schema/nypl_mods" version="3.4" xsi:schemaLocation="http://uri.nypl.org/schema/nypl_mods http://uri.nypl.org/schema/nypl_mods">
<titleInfo ID="titleInfo_0" type="" authority="" usage="primary" supplied="yes" lang="eng" script=""><nonSort/><title>Stratemeyer Syndicate records</title><partNumber/><subTitle/><partName/></titleInfo><typeOfResource ID="typeOfResource_0" usage="primary" manuscript="yes" collection="yes">mixed material</typeOfResource><genre ID="genre_0" authority="lcsh" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85006908" authorityRecordId="sh85006908" usage="primary">Archival materials</genre><genre ID="genre_1" authority="lcsh" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85033035" authorityRecordId="sh85033035">Correspondence</genre><genre ID="genre_2" authority="lcsh" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh99001240" authorityRecordId="sh99001240">Photographs</genre><originInfo ID="originInfo_0"><dateCreated encoding="w3cdtf" point="start">1832</dateCreated><dateCreated encoding="w3cdtf" point="end">1984</dateCreated><publisher/><edition/><issuance/></originInfo><note ID="note_0" type="content">The Stratemeyer Syndicate Records document the literary and business activity of Edward Stratemeyer, his family and colleagues from 1832 until the sale of the StratemeyerSyndicate to Simon and Schuster, Inc. in 1984.  The records include original manuscripts, editorial notes and correspondence, business and administrative files, promotional material, photographs, musical scores and artwork.  The bulk of this material dates from the period 1905-1984, and documents the rise of one of America's largest producers of children's books.  The collection is an important resource for the study of American popular culture, children's literature and the history of publishing.</note><note ID="note_1" type="ownership">MSS 94M6</note><note ID="note_3" type="content">The Stratemeyer Syndicate was established in 1905 by Edward Stratemeyer, a prolific author of juvenile literature. The Syndicate made contracts with large publishing firms, agreeing to supply them with numerous volumes of children's books in series. Stratemeyer hired ghostwriters to produce manuscripts for these books based on his own detailed plot outlines. He wanted entertaining stories that served a serious moral and didactic purpose, and viewed the work of Horatio Alger as a model. Syndicatewriters were paid a one-time fee for each manuscript, received no royalties, and agreed never to reveal their true identities. The Stratemeyer Syndicate flourished by producing such popular children's book series as Tom Swift,The Hardy Boys, The Bobbsey Twins and Nancy Drew. After Edward Stratemeyer's death in 1930, his daughters Harriet Stratemeyer Adams and Edna Stratemeyer Squier ran the business as joint partners. They introduced new book series, revised old titles, marketed books abroad and soldtelevision and film rights. After the death of Edna Stratemeyer Squier in 1974, Harriet Stratemeyer Adams revealed herself to be the pseudonymous Carolyn Keene, author of many Nancy Drew books. In 1979 the Syndicate broke with longtime publisher Grosset &amp; Dunlap and signed a new contract with Simon and Schuster, Inc. In 1984, two years after the death of Harriet Stratemeyer Adams, the Syndicate was sold to Simon and Schuster.</note><note ID="note_4" type="ownership">Simon and Schuster, inc. Gift. 160 linear ft. 375 boxes.</note><identifier ID="identifier_0" type="local_hades" displayLabel="Hades struc ID (legacy)">1924527</identifier><identifier ID="identifier_1" type="local_bnumber" displayLabel="NYPL catalog ID (B-number)">b14520874</identifier><identifier ID="identifier_2" type="local_catnyp" displayLabel="CATNYP ID (legacy)">b6139527</identifier><location ID="location_0"><physicalLocation authority="marcorg" type="repository">nn</physicalLocation><physicalLocation type="division">MSS</physicalLocation><shelfLocator>MssCol 2903</shelfLocator></location></mods>
