<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://uri.nypl.org/schema/nypl_mods" version="3.4" xsi:schemaLocation="http://uri.nypl.org/schema/nypl_mods http://uri.nypl.org/schema/nypl_mods">
<titleInfo ID="titleInfo_0" usage="primary" supplied="no" lang="eng"><nonSort>A </nonSort><title>relation or Iournall of the beginning and proceedings ofthe English plantation setled at Plimoth in New England, by certaine English aduenturers both merchants and others.  With their difficult passage, their safe ariuall, their ioyfull building of, and comfortable planting themselves in the now well defended towne of New Plimoth. As also a relation of fovre seuerall discoueries since made by some of the same English planters there resident. I. In a iourney to Pvckanokick the habitation of the Indians greatest king Massasoyt: as also their message, the answer and entertainment hey had of him. II. In a voyage made by ten of them to the kingdome of Nawset, to seeke a boy that had lost himselfe in the woods: with such accidents as befell them in that voyaage. III. In their iourney to the kingdome of Namaschet, in defence of their greatest king Massasoyt, against the Narrohiggonsets, and to reuenge the suposed death of their interpreter Tisquantum. IIII. Their voyage to the Massachusets, and their entertainment there. With an answer to all such obiections as are any way made against the lawfulnesse of English plantations in those parts.</title></titleInfo><titleInfo ID="titleInfo_1"><title>Mourt's relation.</title></titleInfo><typeOfResource ID="typeOfResource_0">text</typeOfResource><originInfo ID="originInfo_0"><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes">1622</dateIssued><place><placeTerm>London</placeTerm></place><publisher>Printed for Iohn Bellamie, and are to be sold at his shop at the Two greyhounds in Cornhill neere the Royall exchange</publisher></originInfo><note ID="note_0" type="content">"A letter sent from New-England to a friend in these parts,setting forth a briefe and true declaration of the worth of that plantation ... [signed, E. W. (i.e. Edward Winslow)]": p. 60-64.</note><note ID="note_1" type="admin">ps_rbk_cd10_156 and ps_rbk_cd10_163 are both title pages from this book, but don't know which copy it is from.  Parent record created, but need to figure out which copy before attaching image.</note><note ID="note_2" type="content">Caption-title, p. 1: New-England in America. Or A relationof the beginning and proceedings of the English plantationin the north parts of America, called Nevv-England, now inHis Maiesties dominions.</note><note ID="note_3" type="content">Collation: Title-leaf (A&#x2082;?), A&#x2083;, B-L in fours.</note><note ID="note_4" type="content">Copy 1: "Bound by W. Pratt for H. Stevens 1872," in blue morocco, gilt.</note><note ID="note_5" type="content">Copy 1: Maitland Collection.</note><note ID="note_6" type="content">Copy 2: Caption-title, p. [1] A relation or iovrnall of the proceedings of the plantation setled at Plimoth in NewEngland.</note><note ID="note_7" type="content">Copy 2: Imperfect: some edges cropped.</note><note ID="note_8" type="content">Copy 2: Page 1-2 printed form a different setting of type.</note><note ID="note_9" type="content">Dedication signed: R.G.</note><note ID="note_10" type="content">The main part of the narrative was probably written by William Bradford and Edward Winslow. G. Mourt (George Morton?) by whose name the relation is commonly known, seems to have had no other connection with it than that ofwriting the preface and giving the book to the press. cf. Young, Chronicles of the Pilgrim fathers, Boston, 1841, p.[109]-249.</note><note ID="note_11" type="content">"Certaine vsefvl advertisements sent in a letter written by a discreete friend vnto the planters in New England, attheir first setting saile from Southampton ... [signed, I.R. (i.e. John Robinson)]": 4th-6th prelim. leaves.</note><note ID="note_12" type="content">"Reasons &amp; considerations touching the lawfulnesse of remouing out of England into the parts of America [signed,R. C. (i.e. Robert Cushman)]": p. [65]-72. (Page 65 wrongly numbered 85)</note><note ID="note_13" type="content">"To the reader" (3d prelim. leaf) signed: G. Movrt.</note><identifier ID="identifier_0" type="local_hades" displayLabel="Hades struc ID (legacy)">1922529</identifier><identifier ID="identifier_1" type="local_bnumber" displayLabel="NYPL catalog ID (B-number)">b14398413</identifier><identifier ID="identifier_2" type="local_catnyp" displayLabel="CATNYP ID (legacy)">b6007223</identifier><location ID="location_0"><physicalLocation type="division">Rare Book Division</physicalLocation><shelfLocator>*KC 1622 (Mourt's relation. Relation or Iournall of the beginning and proceedings of the English)</shelfLocator></location></mods>
